（毒品实验室 阿姆斯特丹）
《绝地战警2》
（阿姆斯特丹港）
是的 一切都在掌握中
Ja, all this is under control.
（迈阿密 佛罗里达州）
一亿五千万美元和我的毒品就要到手了
A hundred and fifty million dollars and my dope is on the way.
今天会是一个好日子
Today is gonna be a good day.
（墨西哥湾）
我们在北纬25度 西经84度
We are 25 degrees north, 84 degrees west.
货正被抛下水
The cargo's being dropped.
好
Good.
- 你想看看他的枪吗？- 是的
- Do you want to see his gun? - Yeah.
砰 砰
Bang. Bang.
对不起 强尼
Sorry, Johnny.
该死的婊子
Fucking bitches.
红外线探测到水面上有东西
lnfrared's got a live one on the water.
空军「种马」号C-14报告海岸警卫队
Air Force Stallion C-14 to Coast Guard.
我们发现一个目标正朝南佛罗里达350地区快速前进
We've got a fast- moving contact heading 3- 5- 0 toward South Florida.
长官 空军「种马」号发现一个目标正从180方位迅速接近
Captain, Air Force Stallion has a contact at 1- 8- 0 closing fast.
我们是海岸警卫队勇敢者号 要求说明你们的航行意图
This is Coast Guard cutter Valiant. Request to know your intentions.
左前方的船 我们是美国海岸警卫队
VesseI off our port bow, this is U.S. Coast Guard.
截距180 速度17节
lntercept is 1- 8- 0, speed 17 knots.
就这样 伙计们 直升机起飞
Make it so, chief. Scramble the helo.
前方船只 请减速
VesseI off our port bow.
我们是美国海岸警卫队
This is U.S. Coast Guard.
现在请说明你们的意图
Request to know your intentions at this time.
接入
Incoming.
勇敢者 勇敢者
Valiant, Valiant.
我是海岸警卫队6003号
This is Coast Guard 6- 0- 0- 3.
失去目标 完毕
Negative contact with target. Over.
长官 目标失踪了
Captain, we've lost target.
（斯太奥特镇 距迈阿密五英里）
这是你的货和报酬
Here's your delivery and payment.
完了吗？
Is it done?
- 货已装上迪克西七号 - 很好
- Cargo is on Dixie 7. - Okay.
好了 TNT小组 再说一遍 你们给我听好了
All right, TNT, for the millionth time, listen up.
自从911以来 我们已经在水域方面加强了高科技监视
Since 9-11, we've gone hi-tech over water.
毒品走私减少了很多
Dope runners have gone low.
我们的线人说有史以来最大的一宗交易今晚抵达
Our source says the biggest X shipment on record arrives tonight…
我们要找出谁是幕后主使
and we want to know who's behind it.
希望几小时后我们就能找到答案
Hopefully in a few hours we'll have our answer.
我们将从三个方向进攻
We'll hit from three directions.
一支水上小分队 一支汽车武装 还有些人步行进攻
We'll go in with a water team, vehicle assauIt and we got guys on foot.
只有我们的卧底确认毒品后呼叫我们 我们才能行动
We cannot make a move untiI our UCs have lD'd the drugs and called us in.
没有呼叫 我们就撤退 我们将面对的这群人
No call, we back away. And these guys we're going after…
他们有很多武器 而且他们憎恨法律
they got a lot of firepower and they hate the law.
所以你们每个人到了那儿都要当心
So eyes open out there.
B组正在接近
Bravo's on the move.
注意 目标来了
Heads up. Here comes the drop.
见鬼 太亮了
Fuck. My lens is flaring.
我该死的什么都看不到了
I can't see shit.
弟兄们 都到这来
Brothers! Gather around!
嗨
Hey.
- 你怎么不告诉我这儿有个聚会？- 谁管呢
- Why didn't you say there was a rally? - Who's looking?
- 拿着那该死的 我走了 - 该死
- Take that shit. I'm out of here. - Shit.
- 白色力量 - 白色力量
- White power! - White power!
蓝色力量 兔崽子们 迈阿密警察
Blue power, motherfuckers. Miami PD.
噢 该死的 是黑人
Aw, damn. It's the Negroes.
卡斯帕 放下包 A组队长 把人带进来
Casper, drop the bag. Alpha leader, bring them in.
- 坏男孩 - 坏男孩 你们想要做什么？
- Bad boys, - bad boys What you gonna do?
我们来后你们怎么办？
What you gonna do When we come for you?
- 伙计 你该背背歌词 - 我们通常是在合唱的
- Dude, you gotta learn the words. - We usually only do the chorus.
A组队长 进攻吧 带上
Alpha leader, hit it. Bring…
重复你的话
Repeat your transmission.
A组呼叫B4 请继续传话
Alpha leader to Bravo Four, please continue relay.
后援在哪儿？
Where's backup?
- A组队长 快把他人带进来 快 - 迈克 只是有静电干扰
- Alpha leader, bring them in. Hit it. - Mike, I'm only getting static.
全是静电干扰 这该死的无线电
It's all static. The radios are fucked.
- 很好笑吗？啊？- 迈克 他们在哪儿？
- Something funny? Something funny? - Mike, where are they?
抓住你了 黑鬼
Got you, nigger.
- 看来有情况了 - 你不会开枪的
- Looks like we got us a situation here. - You won't shoot.
你以为用枪指着他的头 我就不会把你们打个稀巴烂吗？
You got a gun to his head, so you think I won't splatter you all over?
我就这么想
That's what I think.
我搭挡今晚来这儿就已经准备好送死了
My partner came here tonight prepared to die.
嗨 嗨 噢 别
Hell…hell, no!
像你这样废物 早准备好死了 是吧 马库斯？
lncinerating trash like you. Ready to die, right, Marcus?
- 该死的我干嘛想死啊？- 小子 怕了吧？
- The fuck I want to do that for? - Scared, ain't you, boy?
选择A：把枪放下 告诉我是谁给了你那该死的毒品
A: Put the gun down, tell me who brings this shit in…
也许我会朝你的肩膀开一枪
and maybe I'll just pop one in your shoulder.
或者B：继续逞英雄 然后我会给你胸口来一枪
Or B: Keep acting all Brody and I'll put one in your chest.
或C：你知道 我们可以坐下来谈一谈
Or C: You know, take the time to talk a minute.
缓和一下气氛
You know, de- escalate the situation.
看到了吧 我搭挡又开始说胡话了
See, that's my partner's new spirituaI bulIshit.
而我 则更喜欢用枪说话
Me? I actually prefer shooting motherfuckers.
动静可真大
A lot of movement going on.
我看不见卧底
Can't see the UCs.
- 我觉得出事了 - 先别动
- I think something's going down. - Don't move yet.
迈克 这人正用枪顶着我的脑袋
Mike, the man has a gun to my head.
朝他眼睛打个洞他就会把枪放下了
He'll put it down if a hollow point's in his eye!
你搭挡是个自负的黑鬼
Your partner's a cocky nigger.
- 该死 非得这样吗 伙计？- 看到了？
- Damn. Now, was that necessary, sir? - See?
他不能仅仅当个警察 他还必须是个黑鬼
He can't just be a cop? He got to be a nigga too?
我要做了这傻瓜
I'll hot this fool.
- 迈克 冷静一下 - 冷静？我很冷静
- Calm down. - Calm down? I'm calm.
我很冷静 嗨 哇喔 哇喔
I'm calm! Hey! Whoa! Whoa!
我再也听不下去他的这些废话了
I am way too unstable for that bulIshit.
该死的别乱动 都不许动
Stop all the goddamned movement! Everybody stop moving!
我们不能把你们都放走 但我们会在法庭上想办法的
We can't let you all go, but this shit'll get worked out in court.
我们有自己的权利
We got our rights.
那就先用权利闭上你那该死的嘴
Exercise your right to shut the fuck up.
好吧 好吧 警告你们 我能为你们做的只有这么多了
I'm all right. I'll give you a warning. It's the best I can do for all of youse!
好吗？这家伙疯了
Okay? He's crazy.
- 给你三秒钟 把枪放下 先生 - 他有脾气暴躁的毛病
- You got 3 seconds to drop your gun. - He has anger issue problems!
- 一 - 所以他很每天很早睡觉
- One. - He goes to bed early for this shit!
为的就是起床后能杀他个屁滚尿流
Just to wake up to pop one in a motherfucker!
- 二 - 迈克 别
- Two! - Mike, no!
枪
Gun!
我们上
Rock 'n' roll! Let's go!
杀了这些条子
Kill them cops!
马库斯
Marcus!
上 上 上 快上
Go! Go! Go! Go! Come on, go!
- 趴下 - 放下枪
- Get down! - Drop the…
- 我什么也没干 - 举起手来
- I didn't do shit! - Get your hands up.
我没干
I didn't do it!
该死的无线电坏了 叫些医生来 你们还好吧？
The radios were fucked up. Get some medics over here. You guys okay?
- 是的 我们还好 - 「我们」？你什么意思？
- Yeah, we're fine. - What you mean, "we"?
有人该死地在我屁股上打了一枪
Motherfucker shot me in the ass, man.
- 谁朝你屁股开枪？- 谁？就是你
- Who shot you in the ass? - Who? That "who" would be you.
- 什么？我打中了你？- 没错
- Me? I shot you? - Yeah.
哦 我开了枪 是的 而且开了很多枪
I mean, I was shooting. Yeah, I did a lot of shooting.
但我并不是说我射了你的屁股
But I ain't saying I shot you in the ass.
我说我并没有射你
I ain't saying I didn't shoot you…
但 哦 天啊 你的屁股被人打烂了
but, damn! Somebody shot you in the ass.
你得给我说清楚
Tell me about it.
- 哦 伙计 感觉如何？- 火辣辣的
- Yo, man, how's it feel? - It's hot, man.
我能闻到屁股烧焦的味道
I can smell my ass burning.
迈克 你该亲它一下 就会好了
Mike, you should give it a little kiss so it'll feeI better.
就当我们不在好了
Pretend like we're not even here.
嗨 瑞奇·马丁不是在开演唱会吗？快滚吧
Hey, isn't Ricky Martin having a concert? Get the fuck on.
- 伙计 你老把问题扯到种族主义上去 - 你真可怜
- You always gotta go racial, man. - It's sad, man.
我想没事的 伙计 只打到了肉上 离你的洞洞还远着呢
I think it's cool. It hit the meat. It ain't nowhere near the hole.
只有两个小包？
Two lousy bags?
从阿姆斯特丹运来的最大一批货呢？
What about the biggest shipment of ecstasy to come out of Amsterdam?
让我先照看下我的搭挡 好吗？
Let me worry about my snitch, all right?
出动了那么多人却一无所获
It's a lot of cop work for nothing!
先把你送回家吧
Take your ass home somewhere.
今晚警察抓了我的运货人
Tonight la policia jacked my mules.
谁来告诉我这些条子是怎么得到消息的？
Who can tell me how those jackaIs knew where to bite Johnny Tapia?
说啊
Speak up, cousins.
你很走运 他们没发现迪克西七号上的毒品
You're lucky they did not find my drugs on Dixie 7.
准备换船
Change the boat schedule.
不行 强尼 周四我们还有批货要到
We can't. We got a shipment Thursday.
那到后再换 让他们慢慢猜吧
Change it after. Just keep them guessing.
要知道 不像你 我老爸可没留一大笔钱给我
You know, unlike you, my daddy didn't leave me no trust fund.
我得自己挣钱养活自己 迈克
I got real- world shit to deal with, Mike.
我不是来找刺激的
I'm not in it for the thrilIs.
又是这老一套的鬼话
Same old shit, different day.
好吧 是的 该死 是我射了你 行了吧？
All right, yes, damn. I shot you, all right?
但如果我不开枪 你现在就什么都看不见了
But you'd be seeing nothing at all if I hadn't made my move.
我不知道你为什么发那么大火
I don't know why you acting so angry.
- 哦 你搞错了 我没生气 - 不 你很生气
- You're misinformed. I'm not angry. - No, you're very angry.
不 我不生气
No, I'm not angry.
你很生气 没关系
You are angry. It's okay.
我没生气 只要你别再不停地说「你生气了」
I'm not angry. Except when you keep repeating "you're angry."
那真该死的烦人
That shit's fucking annoying.
就像烤肉会上乱七八糟的事
Like a fucking gnat at a barbecue.
该死的把我烦得够呛
Just bugging the fuck out of me.
好了 我要你跟我说
Good. I want you to say:
我生气了 没关系 我会控制自己的
"I'm angry. It's okay. I'll process my anger.
我爱我自己
I love myseIf.
我根本不知道你在说什么
I don't know what the fuck you mean.
不 你知道我在说什么
Yes, you do know what the fuck I mean.
你才需要那治疗
You're the one that needs therapy.
- 我做过那治疗 - 啥时候？
- I did my therapy. - When?
我那次在机场擅自开枪后 霍华德警长让我去的
Capt. Howard made me do it after I shot them people at the airport.
迈克警官
Officer Mike.
- 帕比 那是「爸爸」的意思 对吧？- 是的
- Papi. That's "daddy, " right? - Yeah.
迈克 你去治疗是为了解决你的心理问题
Mike, you go to therapy to get your issues worked out…
不是为了上你的治疗师
not bang your therapist.
- 瞧 你又开是说下流话了 - 我得生存
- See, now you just talking nasty. - I gotta survive.
我得开始爱护自己了
I gotta start loving me for me.
哦 那听起来像是集体治疗里用的话
That sound like that group thing.
好吧 也许我是参加过一两次集体治疗
Maybe I did the group thing once or twice.
一帮人在一起拥抱 亲吻 就像在搞什么恶心的宗教仪式
A bunch of men hugging and kissing, that's some cult shit.
买了
Buy.
别理他 医生 他只是在小题大作
Ignore him, doc, he's blowing this out of proportion.
我的屁股可不是什么小题 知道吗 迈克？
My ass is what's out of proportion, Mike, okay?
那儿可少了一大块肉
I got a big chunk missing.
事实上就一小块而已
It's actually a small chunk.
你在我们关系中加入这种紧张气氛
This tension you bringing into this relationship…
从长远来看是极为不利的
won't be healthy in the long run.
也许根本不会长远
Maybe there ain't gonna be no long run.
管他呢
Whatever.
他脑子有点
He's seeing a shrink. I mean…
- 冰锥 我是劳瑞 - 嗨 兄弟
- Icepick, Lowrey. - Hey, brother.
两袋 你让我在自己人面前丢光了脸
Two bags? You embarrassed me in front of my people.
等等 兄弟 不不不 伙计 等
Wait, brother. No, no, no, brother. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
不管怎样 你最好去做个祷告
Whatever. You better pray to whoever it is you pray to…
因为在我找到你之前 你只有24小时去找那批货了
because you got 24 hours to find that X before I find you.
警察袭击了我的人
The cops hit my mule.
塔皮亚先生 我也不知道消息是怎么泄露的
Well, Mr. Tapia, I don't know where the heat is coming from.
对我们来说事情都有些蹊跷 不是吗？
It's a delicate situation for both of us, isn't it?
我告诉你 我都查过他们了
I'm telling you, I've checked them.
阿里克斯 看 有个家伙吸毒过量
Alex, look. A guy's OD'ing.
抱歉 我现在得挂了
I'm sorry, I gotta hang up.
有个混蛋想随便死在我这儿
Some fucking punk thinks he can die in my club.
该死迷药简直要了他们的命
Ecstasy fucks them up.
- 把他从这儿弄出去 约瑟夫 - 把他扔到垃圾堆里
- Get him out of here, Josef. - We'll dump him around the block.
扔了他
Dump him.
西德妮姑姑 一个年轻的单身女子
Auntie Syd, it must be so cool.
独自住在纽约一定很酷吧
Young, single, living in New York.
也许身边有一大群的帅小伙
Probably hook up with a lot of cute guys.
就像《欲望都市》里的那样
Just like Sex and the City.
特丽莎 你该停了那该死的有线电视
Theresa, canceI the damn cable.
那么 西德妮姑姑 你也是个警察？
So, Auntie Syd, you're a cop too, huh?
算半个 我为毒品缉查局工作 但只是做做文书什么的
Sort of. I work for the DEA, but I just push a lot of papers.
- 没什么好兴奋的 - 你还是继续做你的文书好了
- Nothing exciting. - Well, you keep pushing papers.
那样我就不用为我妹妹和犯罪打交道而担心了
Don't have to worry about my little sister fighting crime.
对吧？
Okay?
很可能受伤的
Possibly getting hurt.
詹姆斯 把我的镙丝刀拿来 该死的镙栓
James. Get my screwdriver. Damn bolts.
别理他 因为受了伤 他现在变得很刻薄
Ignore him. He's being mean because he got injured.
- 你没事吧？- 他的伤没事 只是
- Are you okay? - His wound is fine. It's…
呃 某些地方被感染了
other things that were affected.
- 特丽莎 - 怎么了？
- Theresa! - What?
你 只是些神经受了伤 仅此而已
You- It's just nerve damage, that's all.
你会毁了我
Y'all not gonna spoil it.
一会儿回来我再跟你说
I'll talk to you about it.
面包圈
It's a donut.
是个医疗用具
It's a medicaI thing.
我从一个孕妇商店里买来的 你知道孕妇们常用它的
I got it from a maternity store. You know, pregnant women use it.
你可以把臀部的一半放在这儿 那样就能减轻另一半的负担
They can put one cheek here. It take pressure off the other cheek.
- 给你的 伙计 - 想得真周到
- For you, dog. - Thoughtful.
听着 伙计
Look, man…
昨晚 我从你眼里看到了某些不一样的东西
last night there was something different in your eyes.
我有神灵在保护 迈克 你知道吗？
You know, Mike, I had an epiphany. You know?
- 我意识到你是个神秘的家伙 - 是的 我知道
- I realized you're an enigma. - Yeah, I could see that.
上帝派你来考验我 但你猜怎么着？
God sent you here to test me. But guess what?
你毁灭不了我 迈克 不
You not gonna break me, Mike. No.
那是西德妮吗？
Is that Syd?
- 哦 是西德妮 - 现在不是时候
- That's Syd. - Now's not a good time.
迈克 听着 现在不是时候
Mike, listen, now's not a good time.
扔过来 传给我
Hit me, hit me, hit me.
别在房间里传球
No throwing balIs in the house.
- 你好 特丽莎 - 你好
- What's up, Theresa? - Hey.
哦 他们没告诉我有烤芋头叶吃
Aw, they ain't tell me it was a luau.
哦 西德妮 等等 别急 等等
Syd, hold up. Hold up. Hold on.
注意点 女士 嗨 等等 等一下
Behave yourseIf, girl. Hey, hold up. Hold up. Hold up.
哦 看看你 看看你
Oh, look at you. Look at you.
哦 好了 好了 我明白了
Oh, okay. Okay. I see now.
你还没把纽约的事告诉马库斯
You didn't tell Marcus about New York.
- 他知道的 那我们呢？- 我们俩的事你说了吗？
- He knows about New York. - About us? You told him about us?
不 但他知道纽约的事
No, he knows about New York.
要知道那是个好地方 上个月我还和一个证人睡了一觉
You know, it's a nice city and that I dropped a witness off last month.
迈克的嘴可真甜
Mike is so sweet.
- 太甜会把你的牙蛀坏的 - 你告诉他了吗？
- So sweet he make your teeth rot. - So have you told him yet?
亲爱的 马上 好吗？我马上告诉他
Baby, soon, okay? Real soon.
你就要调走了 不再是他搭挡了 你必须要让他知道
He needs to know you're transferring and won't be his partner anymore.
特丽莎 时机很重要
Theresa, timing is everything.
现在马库斯正生我气呢 可是
Marcus is not very happy with me right now.
不不 西德妮 我告诉你
No, no, Syd, I'm telling you,
那个一瘸一拐的家伙 现在可正在气头上呢
that is Scarface limping around in there.
我们得给他点时间 让他的屁股好好恢复
We need to give that boy a few minutes to let his butt heaI up good.
我们彼此相爱 还有什么大不了的？
We like each other. What's the big deal?
我现在就去告诉他 我不想再隐瞒了
I'm just gonna go tell him right now, because this is dumb.
不不不 还是我来说吧
Hold up. Hold up. I'm gonna tell him.
我不会不告诉他的 我怎么可能隐瞒呢？
It ain't like I won't tell him. How am I not tell him?
- 几时？- 给我一分钟
- When? - I need a minute.
说实话 我和他之间还有点小误会 再给我点时间
Straight up. We're not vibing right now. I just need a minute.
迈克 他是我哥哥 对吧？
Mike, he's my brother, okay?
所以没什么好怕的 勇敢些 老兄
Don't be scared. Toughen up, chief.
哦 嗨 嗨 我可没说我害怕
Whoa. Hey. Hey, I ain't say I was scared.
只是 你哥有些不对劲
Just… There's something wrong with your brother.
迈克 听说你上个月去了纽约
So, Mike, I understand you were in New York last month.
是的 我
Yeah, I was…
- 你还记得我做的事吗？- 不
- Remember I did the thing? - No.
记得吗？
You remember?
你们俩真该在一起 你们很相配
The two of you should've gotten together. That would've been nice.
西德妮 我从没告诉过你 迈克去过纽约
I never told you Mike was in New York.
哦 你知道吗 迈克？
Well, you know what, Mike?
西德妮将在镇里再住一个月
Syd, she's gonna be in town, what, another week?
你不如带她到处看看 那一定很棒
Why don't you show her around? That'd be nice.
好主意
That would be so great.
是 是 行 呃 马库斯 我和
Yeah. Yeah, I could- Well, me and…
马库斯 你有什么东西要给她看吗？
Marcus, you want to show her some stuff?
哦 因为我是来镇里度假的
Yeah, because I'm in town on vacation.
我住在一个最棒的旅馆里
I'm staying at the most amazing hotel.
那景色 那游泳池 哦 上帝啊
The view, the pool. Oh, my God.
我们这儿也有游泳池
We got a pooI right here.
伙计 那个不算游泳池
That ain't exactly a pool, man.
只不过是个用蓝塑胶布围起来的小坑坑
That's like a big- ass puddle wrapped in blue plastic.
老爸 你买这房子的时候 就没有像样点的游泳池？
Didn't they have any good pools when you bought this one?
梅根 这泳池花了我3900美元
Megan, that pool cost $3900.
好吧 那一个像样点的要花多少钱？
Okay, so how much do the good pools cost?
- 行了 亲爱的 - 那要好大一笔钱呢 知道吗？
- It's all right, baby. - It is kind of whack, huh?
我还有个约会 很高兴再次见到你 迈克
I gotta go meet somebody. It was nice seeing you again, Mike.
我也是
Nice- Good to see you.
你要去哪儿？
Where you going?
- 再见 亲爱的 - 再见
- Bye, sweetie. - Bye.
我还以为你是来度假的
I thought you were on vacation.
很高兴你能来这儿 迈克
So glad you could join us, Mike.
我来告诉你 多花点时间 做这事能让我们的关系更加牢固
I'm telling you, spending time like this make a partnership strong.
迈克 到我的破泳池边来谈谈好吗？
Mike, can I see you by my stupid pool?
什么事 伙计？
What's the deal, baby?
你为什么总是像这儿的主人一样跑过来？
Why you gotta always come over here and try to take over, Mike?
- 你在说什么？- 伙计 这是我的家 明白吗？
- What are you talking about? - This is my family, man. Okay?
- 你到底在说什么啊？- 我宁静的港湾
- What are you talking about? - My place of peace.
你吃药了吗？
Are you taking medication?
你得按时吃药 对吧？
You taking medicine for the thing, right?
- 我怎么了？- 算了 忘了它吧
- What'd I do? - Forget it. Just forget it.
- 我做什么了？- 马森 去把它捡回来
- What'd I do? - Mason. Go fetch.
哦 上帝啊
Oh, shit!
哦 真有趣
Now, that shit is funny.
这真该死的有趣
That's some funny shit.
哦 伙计 等等
Oh, man, hold up.
哦 我是劳瑞 怎么？
Yo, Lowrey, you hot.
3900美元 3900美元啊
Thirty- nine hundred dollars. Thirty- nine hundred.
这次你最好向上帝祈祷 嗨 伙计 快把自己擦干
You better pray to God you right this time. Yo, dry off, sweetheart.
冰锥说海地帮要去打劫 我们快走
lcepick said the Haitian Zoepounds about to do a rip. Let's move.
好了 伙计们 机灵点 跟我说话
All right, guys, smarten up. Talk to me.
小心点 祝你们好运
Eyes on, agents. Good luck.
我是105
This is 105.
他们回来了
They're backing in.
我这儿看得很清楚
I got a good look.
- 我们的视野很好 - 好吧 我们进去
- We got a good eyeball. - All right, we're in.
怎么样了？
What's up?
纽约方面大力推荐你
You come highly recommended out of New York.
你在那儿为我们的俄罗斯朋友干得很好
You did some good jobs for our Russian crew up there.
你多大了？
How old are you?
足够大了
Old enough.
来吧 你们要想把这些都运走就得快点
Come on. If you want to move this stuff you gotta do it quick.
哦 设备不错啊 你可以开始点了
Wow, nice getup. You can start to run these through.
让我看看你的家伙如何？
I'd like to see how your machine works.
喔 好像这听上去有点黄
Ooh, that sounded dirty.
让我看看你的家伙如何？宝贝儿
"I would like to see how your machine works, baby."
我其实并不粗俗
I wouldn't be so crude.
我的意思是 实际上我很高雅
I mean, I'm more of a refined kind of a human being.
你跳芭蕾吗？
You follow ballet?
我有三个表妹在莫斯科的波尔肖大剧院跳芭蕾
Three of my cousins are dancing with the Bolshoi Theatre in Moscow.
我也喜欢嘻哈音乐
I like hippie- hop too.
你给了五千块
I gave you 5000.
你只给了我四千九
You gave me 4900.
- 我给了你五千块 - 四千九
- I gave you 5000. - 4900.
- 五千块 - 再数数
- 5000. - Count it.
你再跟我耍花招 就找别人交易去吧
If you want to fuck with me again, find yourseIf another chump.
好吧
Okay.
- 几个人？- 三个
- How much? - Three.
哦 看看 到处都是钱 快收拾一下
Look at this. Money everywhere. Clean it up.
好了 我们要换三百万 明白吗？
Okay, we want to change a little over $3 million, all right?
你给我的纽约朋友干过多少事？
How many jobs did you do with my friends up there in New York?
很多
Quite a few.
你对我的态度会影响很多事
How you behave with me has consequences for a lot of people.
是你来找我的 而不是我找你
You found me, not the other way around.
你要我把小面额换成大钞交给第三方
You need me to change small bilIs to large ones and deliver to a third party.
我打赌 他一定很想马上收到钱
I bet he'd like his money in a timely fashion.
如果钱迟了 那是你的事 跟我没关系
Delivery's late, it's your ass, not mine.
这儿有五万一百元的 换你五万十元的
Here's 50, 000 in 100s for your 50, 000 in 10s.
第三方的钱装在这五个箱子里
Third party takes his million in these five briefcases here.
- 我希望你没被搞糊涂 老板 - 我讨厌算术
- I hope I'm not losing you, chief. - I hate math.
我们帮你换了三百万
So for your $3 million that we shrunk for you…
你拿走应得的二百万
you get 2 million in clean money back.
减去我们应得的三十万
Less our percentage: $300, 000.
- 我会把这些送到你上家的手里 - 阿里克斯
- I'll be delivering these to your dealer. - Alexei.
- 什么事？- 我们付出的太多了
- What? - We're giving too fucking much away.
所有风险都是我们承担的
We take all the risk.
我们的供应商拿走了太多的利润
And our suppliers take too much of our profit.
好吧 打电话给上面 我们要重新商量一下
Yeah, we'll call the general, renegotiate.
他是商人 我们也是
He's a businessman, we're businessmen.
好吧 给他打电话
Yeah, call him.
你打
You call.
伙计们 我正在送钱的路上
Agents, we're on the move to the money drop.
走了
Forward.
嗨 伙计 卡车开走了 我们得跟上
Hey, man, the truck's leaving. We're going to follow it.
别丢了
Don't lose that truck.
跟上那卡车 跟上它
Follow that truck. Follow that truck.
是的 他们上路了 看来冰锥的情报没错
Yep, they saddling up. Look like Icepick came through.
他们要劫谁的货？
Wonder whose shit they about to rip now?
猎鹰一号 你看见她了吗？
Falcon One, do you see her?
正在监视
Stand by.
我可不想被发现 挨一枪
I don't want to get spotted, take a burn.
他们是群海盗 什么都抢
Zoepound a bunch of pirates, man. SteaI anything.
十点方向有辆黑色的雪佛兰Suburban
Black Suburban at 10 o'clock.
哦 来吧 宝贝儿 停到顶上
Oh, come on, baby. Park it at the top.
罗伯特 她朝你来了
Roberto, she's coming to you.
我看见了
I got her.
这里是猎鹰一号 伙计们 我看见她上来了
This is Falcon One, guys. I got her coming up.
注意了 伙计们 又来了辆橙色的大跑车
Heads up, guys. I got an orange muscle car.
看来里面有三个黑人
Looks to be three black male occupants.
这我可没料到 通知他们
It's out of our field of vision. Bring it up.
好的 注意了 你们后面来了三个不明身份的人
All right, be aware, we got three bogeys unidentified.
伙计们 来了三个可疑的家伙 他们散开了
Guys, we got three bogeys. They're splitting up. They're moving.
小心了他们正在靠近 该死 该死
Be aware. They're approaching- Shit. Shit.
- 该死 他开了枪 - 该死
- Fuck, it's a hit! - Shit.
我们的人中枪了 中枪了
Agent down. Agent down.
罗伯特 该死快跟上他们
Roberto, fucking follow them!
- 我来了 我来了 - 该死
- I'm on it! I'm on it! - Shit!
待在这儿
Stay here!
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
是西德妮
It's Syd!
走 快走
Move! Move!
伙计 你老妹在里面干嘛？
Man, what is your sister into?
人行道 人行道
Sidewalk! Sidewalk!
闪开 闪开 闪开
Move! Move!
该死
Shit.
- 该死 - 运河街需要支援 现在
- Shit! - I need backup on Canal, now!
准备开枪
You just get ready to shoot.
警察
Police!
停车
Stop the car!
该死 给他看警徽干嘛 他有枪 射他
Man, your badge?! He has a gun! Shoot him!
迈克 她有麻烦了
Mike, she's in trouble, man.
不 快让开
Move! Get out of the way!
我觉得我就快疯了
I think I done just got mad.
- 枪 枪 枪 - 抓住了
- Gun! Gun! Gun! - Hold on.
现在 给他们看你的警徽
Now show them your badge!
- 你真该死的疯了 - 我知道了
- This shit is crazy. - I know, right?
让开 让开
Move! Move!
都蹲下
Get the world down here!
该死
Shit!
上 上
Go! Go!
滚出来
Get out!
你 开车
You, drive!
走
Go!
快 快 快 迈克 追上那狗娘养的 追上他
Go, go, go, Mike! Punch that shit! Punch it!
杀了那婊子
Kill the fucker!
该死
Shit!
让开 让开
Move! Move!
- 别丢了她 迈克 - 我正在追呢
- Don't lose her, Mike! - This is what I do!
该死 该死
Shit! Shit.
我一定要宰了他
Definitely shoot that motherfucker that just…
哦 上帝 我的车灯
Oh, man, my headlight.
开枪啊 开枪啊 射 射啊
Shoot back! Shoot back! Shoot! Shoot!
哦 你 你在干什么 伙计
What the-?! What are you doing, man?
- 是 是我不好 - 往外射啊
- That's my bad. - Shoot outside!
你该死给我小心点
Pay attention to what you're doing.
这些该死的把链子给解了
These dudes is off the chain!
上帝啊 见鬼
Jesus! Fuck!
- 真该死的糟透了 - 是的 一会儿还会更糟
- This is some sick shit! - Yep, it's about to get sicker.
小心 小心
Watch out! Watch out!
哦 天
Oh, sh-!
- 哦 他们不会那么干了 - 哦 不 又来了
- Oh, they are not about to do that. - Hell, yes, they are!
下去
Go!
- 你看见了 他们在扔车 - 我看到了
- You see that?! - They throwing cars! How can I not?!
- 我只想帮忙 懂吗 - 你知道怎么帮吗？
- I'm just trying to help, okay?! - You know what'd be fucking helpful?
闭上你的鸟嘴 让我开车
Just shut the fuck up and let me drive! Let's try that!
嗨 来啊 伙计 尖叫啊
Hey, come on, man, with the screaming shit!
我要集中精力避开那些该死的车
I'm concentrating on dodging these fuckers.
放松
Just relax.
- 哦 翻过去了 - 那该死的车翻过去了
- That was a flip! - That motherfucker flipped!
- 吓我一大跳 - 它差点撞到我的头
- That one puckered up my butthole. - Almost fucking crushed my head.
游艇
The boat!
我甩了他们 是的 我把你的货带到了备用交货点
I lost them. Yeah, I've got your cargo to the backup drop point.
所有人注意了 嫌犯仍然在逃
Attention all units, suspects still at large.
她在那儿
There she is.
这到底是怎么回事 西德妮
What the fuck is going on, Syd?
差点要了所有人的命
Some desk you're driving.
离开这儿 我是卧底 请叫你的人走开
Get over here, I'm undercover. And please call off your dogs.
我有毒品缉查局的人保护 别砸了我的案子
I got DEA watching my back, so don't blow my case.
- 我们救了你的命 - 我很感激
- We saved your life. - And I appreciate that.
但我不喜欢你们俩像现在这样跟着我
What I don't appreciate is you two following me here…
差点砸了一个准备了五个月的案子
nearly burning a case that took five months to set up.
那么我们一直在互相说谎？对吗？
So now we lie to each other? Is that what we do?
- 你要我怎么办？- 马库斯 好吧
- What do you want me to do? - All right.
- 去死 迈克 她错了 - 冷静一下 放松
- Fuck that, Mike, she's wrong. - Calm down. Relax.
西德妮 车里有毒品吗？
Syd, are there drugs in that truck?
- 是现金 - 给谁的？
- There's cash. - Where's it going?
- 我不能告诉你 - 为什么？
- I can't tell you that. - Why not?
因为那是我的工作 如果我想保住饭碗就必须遵守规定
Because I have a career and if I want to keep it, I have rules to follow.
那是什么意思？
What's that mean?
意思是我收到命令 无论如何不能把情报透露给迈阿密警方
My orders are, under no circumstances share information with Miami PD…
- 因为他们有人泄密 - 哦 那我现在是迈阿密警察？
- because they got too many leaks. - Oh. I'm Miami PD now?
你一定忘了我还是你哥 对吧？
You done forgot I'm your big brother, huh?
知道吗 西德妮 你刚才的行为简直是太鲁莽了
You know what, Syd, that shit you did was reckless…
又愚蠢 又危险 懂吗？
it was stupid and it was dangerous. Okay?
我要告诉妈妈 知道吗 我一定会把这事说出去的
I'm telling Mommy. Okay? I'm definitely leaking that shit.
嗨 马库斯
Hey, Marcus…
西德妮 拜托 他也有他的道理
Syd, come on, he got a point.
你哥哥爱你
Your brother loves you.
更不用说那还是他的职责
Not to mention a little thing called professionaI courtesy.
你闯进了别人的地盘 该让主人知道
You bouncing in somebody's yard, you should let them know about it.
第一次用枪？
First time using your gun?
嗨 你干得很漂亮
Hey, you handled yourseIf very well.
很可惜你搭挡没注意到
Too bad your partner didn't notice.
谢谢
Thanks.
你以为你能轻易脱身？一个你跟了五个月的案子？
Think you get off that easy? You been working this for five months?
为什么在纽约时你没告诉我？
How come you ain't tell me in New York?
- 你会说什么？- 我会
- What would you have said? - I would've…
我会告诉你这工作不好干 你知道
I'd have let you know this job is rugged, you know.
很危险 如果你出了什么事 我会
It's dangerous. And if something happen to you I might…
所以我什么都没说
Exactly why I didn't say anything.
有人偷了你的钱
Somebody's stealing your money.
交易完成了 我得走了
The drop's done. I gotta go.
谢谢
Thanks.
在她出事前我们得把这案子解决了
We gotta close this case before it get her killed.
是的 毫无疑问
Yeah, no doubt.
准备好回局里一趟了吗？我们得给自己擦擦屁股
You ready to go back to the station, get our asses whupped?
我想我们会没事的
I think we gonna be all right.
伙计们
Fellas.
你们的任务内容是什么？
What's your job description?
不 你们俩
No, you two.
你们的任务内容是什么？
What is your job description?
我来告诉你们
I'll tell you.
战术扫毒组
Tactical Narcotics Team.
关键字是 战术
Keyword: "tactical"
运用精妙的战术取得胜利
"Displaying finesse and subtlety in achieving a goal!"
告诉我 先生们
Tell me, gentlemen…
今天你们的精妙战术体现在哪儿了？
what was subtle about your work today?
二十二辆汽车
Twenty-two cars…
还有一艘游艇 就这些？
and a boat, totaled?
你们是怎么把那艘游艇弄沉的？
How did you sink a boat?
我们没把它弄沉
We didn't sink it.
好吧 先说好消息 感谢上帝没有警察牺牲
All right, the positive. Thank God no cops died.
坏消息是 有个高级警官一直跟在我屁股后面
The negative: I got a police commissioner so far up my ass…
他怎么说我就得怎么做
if he spits it's coming out of my mouth.
但是我知道事情总是有两面性的
But I know that there's always two sides to a story.
那么 说说你们的故事吧
So, what's yours?
哦 好的 当时我正在参加个家庭烤肉会
Well, I was at a family barbecue.
我们得到情报 海地帮
We got a tip that the Zoepounders…
正准备抢劫一个大佬的钱或者是毒品
were gonna do a hit on cash or drugs from this big-time X-Man.
他们把街头毒贩叫做大佬
That's what they call a ecstasy dealer on the streets.
马库斯 我知道他们怎么这么叫这帮人
Marcus, I know what they call them.
这就是为什么我才是警长 行了
That's why I'm captain. It's cool.
那么你们查到了毒品
So you got the drugs.
没有毒品 哦 好的 那么钱呢？
No drugs. Oh, okay. All right. How about the money?
- 没有钱？- 没有
- No money. - Nope.
那谁是大佬？
Then who is this X-Man?
长官 我当时正在举行家庭烤肉会 所以我
Captain, I was at a family barbecue. So I…
我们不知道 但我们会查清楚的
We don't know, but we are going to find out.
好吧 那么那些
Well, then all that…
- 毫无价值吗？- 那不全都是我们干的
- was for nothing? - We didn't do all of that.
如果你凑近点的话 看 停一下 我来指给你看
If you look close-Watch. Hold up. Let me show…
全是缉毒局的人 等 等等 就在这儿
There's DEA all over. Wait, the- Wait, hold up.
缉毒局？怎么没有通知我？
The DEA? Without consuIting me?!
这儿 在这儿就有辆他们的车
That's a DEA car right there.
天 该死
Christ! Fuck!
警长 不 压一压你的穴位
Cap. No. Remember your pressure points.
我 我要做做练习
Do my… My exercises.
对你的小弟们叫去吧
Holler at your boy.
二万一千美元？什么
Twenty-one thousand? What?!
哦 真该亲亲我的屁股
Oh, kiss my black ass.
那是我的底限了
It was the dashboard.
- 知道吗？- 好多了
- You know what? - Better.
是的 你们会拿到钱的
Yeah, you'll get your money.
已经派人给你们送钱去了
Somebody's on they way with your money.
长官 我们是不是来谈谈赔偿损失的事
Is it possible we could discuss potential reimbursement…
我们不赔偿私人财产 这就是为什么我们开的是警车
We don't cover personaI property. That's why we drive police cars.
现在我们怎么办？
So where do we go from here?
海地帮的人知道准确的交货时间和地点
Zoepounders knew exactly when to hit the drop, where to hit the drop…
所以我们想他们一定也知道钱在哪儿
so we figure they know where the cash is.
我们找到钱的话 就能找到那个大佬
We find the cash, we find the X- Man.
嗨 我可不想参加这游戏 懂吗？我这儿有三个员警生命垂危
Hey, I'm through playing games, all right? I have three cops critical.
在我这儿每天都有孩子被毒品害死
I got kids dying on my streets from souped-up X.
我可不想让这帮禽兽毁了我的城市
I do not want these animals taking over my city.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
所以 我要你们俩尽你们全力 不惜一切 现在就去办吧
So I want you guys to do whatever you do, whatever it takes, but do it now.
这儿不太好 老板
It's not good, boss.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
该死的老鼠竟敢咬我的钱
Fucking ratones eating my fucking money.
卡洛斯 这真是个愚蠢的问题
Carlos, this is a stupid fucking problem to have.
可不管怎么说 总是个问题
But it is a problem nonetheless.
该死的老鼠
Rat fuckers.
老板 真他妈疯狂
Boss, it ended up crazy.
那个给俄国佬做事的黑妞简直是个疯子
This black chica working for the Russians was a maniac lunatic.
她救了你的钱
She saved your money.
她干掉了些海地人 还把货送到了交易点
She wasted some Haitians and got the load to the drop.
还有 罗伯特看见了这两个黑帮老乡
Also, Roberto saw these two crazy gangbanger homeys.
- 哦 该死 - 发疯似的又追又打
- Oh, shit. - Yeah. Chasing and shooting.
以前我有过这样的问题吗？没有
Old days, did I have this problem? No.
只要把毒品空运进来再把钱用船运走就行了
Just fly the drugs in and ship the money out.
但现在 该死的美国海岸警卫队把水域封得太紧了
Now American security's so goddamned tight over the water…
而在天上
and in the sky…
那些老鼠在钱运到古巴前就会把它们吃光的
that the rats eat my money before I can get it to Cuba.
- 看见了吗？- 火爆撞车
- You see? - Fiery crash…
甚至连我的钱运过这城市都得弄出点新闻来
I can't even get my money across town without making the news.
嗨 伙计
Hey, man. Man.
告诉我
Tell me…
我是不是该担心了？
should I be worried?
- 不 老板 - 给我闭嘴
- No, boss. - Shut the fuck up.
在迈阿密 居然有人抢我的货
People is trying to jack my loads here in Miami.
我拥有这该死的城市 明白吗？
I own this fucking town. You see?
这是我的地盘
This is my town.
哦 我的天 粉红
Oh, my God. Pink.
粉红 尼娜 粉红色 不是淡蓝色
Pink, niсa, pink. Pink. No powder blue.
粉红的更漂亮
Pink is prettier.
可店里的女士说我看起来像个模特
But the lady at the store said I look like a model.
你很幸运 你的母亲是我母亲的表亲
You're lucky your mother was my mother's cousins.
别理罗伯特
Don't pay attention to Roberto.
此外 模特都是些肮脏的家伙
Besides, modeIs are fiIthy creatures.
你看起来更像个天使
You look more like an angel.
- 你觉得呢 卡洛斯？- 当然
- What do you think, Carlos? - Of course.
- 罗伯托 你怎么想？- 真漂亮死了
- Roberto, what do you think? - It's fucking beautiful.
在我的小甜心前说话文明点
Talk polite in front of my little bonbon…
要不然我让你断子绝孙
or I'm gonna chop your balIs off.
说真的 我不介意 你那些精神指引之类的玩意儿
For real, I'm straight with all your spirituaI enlightenment and that shit.
可我必须得知道
But I need to know
如果有个家伙 拿着把枪向我冲来 你会把那蠢货宰了吗
if a crackhead rolIs to me with a.9, you'll cook that fool.
当然 我会朝他的腿来上一枪
No question about it. Shoot him in the leg.
拜托 别只是朝腿上打啊
Come on with that leg shit.
- 每个人都该获得一点起码的尊重 - 可我的尊严呢？
- Everybody deserves a little dignity. - What about my dignity?
那家伙会失去膝盖骨 而我则会被装到裹尸袋里去
Your crackhead will be missing a kneecap. I'll be in a body bag.
- 太悲哀了 - 什么太悲哀了？
- So sad. - What's so sad?
看来你的情绪治疗不起作用
Your untreated control issues.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你到底是什么意思？
What in the hell is that supposed to mean?
你还是婴儿的时候 你妈肯定没让吃她的奶
Your mama probably refused you her tit when you were a baby.
所以你发育不良 只能高中毕业
You grew up a malnourished high-school softie.
端着枪 穿着又小又紧的T恤
Got your gun, little tight T-shirt…
成了一个报复狂
and became a overcompensating tough guy.
请你以后别再提我妈的奶
That is the last time you will ever refer to my mother's titties.
你甚至连想都不许想
I don't even want them up in your head.
我说了那么多话 迈克 可你就听见「奶」
You know, I said all that, Mike, and all you heard was "titties."
伙计 你不可能一直控制我的思想 迈克
Man, you can't keep suppressing my spiritual growth, Mike.
你必须把我母亲的「奶」 从你的精神分析里排除出去
You need to suppress my mother's titties out of your psychoanalysis.
你只要记住一件事 伙计 我不会和你做一辈子搭档的
You just remember one thing, my friend. I may not always be here.
你好吗 冰锥？
What's up, Icepick?
耶稣会指引你 我的兄弟 请进
Jesus is the way, my brothers. Step inside.
你刚刚在「迈克叔叔」 的黑名单上占据了第一名
You just went number one on Uncle Mike's shit list.
- 我们只拿到两小袋毒品 伙计 - 我的兄弟们
- We got two lousy bags, man. - My brothers.
海地人 金色的辫子 他在哪儿？
Haitian blond with dreads. Where is he?
金辫子？
Blondie Dread?
这消息可贵了
He's very expensive.
你 还有你 必须为我做点事
You and you have to do something for me.
哦 你正试图恐吓我吗？
Oh, you trying to get gangster on me like that?
- 是的 他是在玩恐吓 - 那我们可能该
- Yeah, he went gangster. - So we should probably…
- 而我们想做 你明白了吗？- 是的 当然
- So we want to do the…You got them? - Yeah, sure.
我和我的搭档 我们是迈阿密警局 双人舞蹈组合
Me and my partner, we're on the Miami PD tandem dance team.
我们有固定的表演套路 我们赢得过所有本地的表演奖
We got a routine. We won all the local talent shows.
我们在考虑进入国家队
We thinking about going national.
你想给他展示展示吗？
You want to show him some of the routine?
热热身 别碰坏了东西
Warm it up. Don't hurt nothing.
喔 喔 看看这个 看看这个
Yo, yo, watch this. Watch this.
好戏来了 看好了
This the shit right here. This is the shit.
- 你们在我店里干了什么？- 看他这个旋转舞步
- What you doing to my shop?! - Watch this spin.
等等
Wait.
- 你们在干什么？- 让我也来露两手
- What are you doing?! - Oh, give me some.
你们会毁我了的店 住手
You're ruining my shop. Stop!
- 来段舞蹈 - 我要把这房子拆掉
- Do the dance thing. - I'm gonna bring the house down.
住手 住手
Stop! Stop!
他住在幢粉红的房子里 离这里八个街区 在卡尔大街
He lives in a pink house eight blocks from here on Carl Street.
一
One…
- 警察 趴下 - 警察
- Police! Get down. - Police!
谁？谁在我的房子里
Who that? Who in my house?!
- 我是魔鬼 是谁在问？- 魔鬼在这里不受欢迎
- I'm the devil, who's asking?! - The devil is not welcome here!
你刚在他的房子里 称呼自己为魔鬼？该死
You got to call yourself the devil in his house?! Shit!
你们怎么敢进我的屋子
You're in my house!
都是你们自己惹的祸
This is all your fault!
- 你还跑到我的国家来了呢 - 去死 那又怎么样？
- You're in my country, though. - Fuck you, how's that?
- 我会杀了你 混蛋 - 你们的国家是狗屎
- I'm gonna kill you, motherfucker! - Your country, my ass!
- 去死 - 我去死？你去死吧
- Fuck you. - Fuck me? Fuck you!
你算个屁
You no problem!
迈克 你不这么火爆不行吗？
Mike, do you have to be so combative?
混蛋
Fucking-!
你在骂我婊子吗？
You calling me a bitch?!
要么合作 要么去死 伙计
Do or die, man!
脑袋来颗子弹 会让你的护照延期
A bullet in the head'll really mess up your extensions.
让你的枪子儿吃屎去吧
Take your bullet and eat that shit, man.
这个怎么样？
How about that?
什么情况？
What the fuck?
先生 我们只是想谈谈
Sir, we just want to talk.
你想谈谈吗？好吧 来吧 来啊
You want to talk?! Well, go ahead. Go ahead.
我们不是移民局的
We're not lmmigration.
他们听不见你说话 因为他们正对着你开火呢
They can't hear you because they're still shooting at you.
该死的海地人躲在间该死的破房子里
Fucking Haitians in a fucking little-ass room…
拿着该死的枪 该死
with fucking guns. Shit!
得给你们点颜色瞧瞧了 该死 就现在
Got to make it home to my babies. Damn, now.
混蛋 你们杀了我的兄弟
Motherfucker! You killed my brother!
那是个婊子
That's a bitch!
杀了他们 杀了他们
Shoot them. Fucking shoot them.
他们打到我了 他们打中我了 伙计
They shot me. They got me, man. Yo!
逮到你了
Got you.
哦 混蛋 该死混蛋
Oh, shit! Motherfucker!
他们杀了他
They killed the boy!
他们要杀了我
They kill me!
他们在杀所有的人
They're killing everybody!
该死混蛋
Motherfucker!
我的眼睛
My eyes!
我会杀了你的 混蛋
I'm gonna kill you, motherfucker!
来 过来杀我吧 你这混蛋
Come. Come kill me, motherfucker.
来吧 你别想活捉我
Come. You don't take me alive.
给你三秒钟放下武器
You got three seconds to drop your weapon!
我有个礼物给你
I got a present for you!
- 一份不错的礼物 - 一
- A nice present for you! - One!
- 二 - 我会杀了你
- Two! - I'm gonna kill you.
别开枪 别开枪 伙计 别杀我
Don't shoot. Don't shoot, man. Don't kill me.
- 子弹和所有 原谅我 - 你没事吧 伙计？
- Bullets and all. Excuse me. - You all right, man?
向那位先生道歉 向那位先生道歉
Apologize to that man. Apologize to that man.
道歉 快
Apologize! Apologize.
嗨 听着 我欠你
Hey, listen, I owe you…
是这样 你那么无礼
It's just that, you know, you was disrespect…
可那不意味着 我就因此拥有权利 我没有
But that don't mean it give me the right, though. It don't.
原谅我
Excuse me. Whoosah. Whoosah.
该死混蛋
Whoosah, motherfucker!
看 有趣的是 他却是我们中唯一没发脾气的
See, the interesting thing is he's the one of us that's not pissed off.
- 我什么也不知道 - 我也还什么都没问你呢
- I don't know nothing. - I didn't ask you no question yet!
- 我什么都不知道 - 已经开始撒慌了？
- I don't know nothing. - Lying already?
- 不 - 你对送货知道多少？
- No, get… - How did you know about the drop?
- 我什么都不知道 - 别再撒谎了
- I don't know nothing! - Stop lying!
你知道吗？
Do you know anything?
我会好好来问的 你知道些什么？
I'm gonna be nice about it. Do you know anything?
让我们问问其他的嫌犯
Let's ask some other suspects.
嗨 看啊 伙计 我靠
Hey, look, man, fuck it.
让我们试试这个 让我们和他的老乡们聊聊
Let's try this. Let's talk to his homeys.
嗨 看看这儿 伙计
Hey, look here, man.
你能告诉我 是谁开的那辆黑色的雪佛兰Suburban吗？
Can you tell me who was driving the black Suburban?
哦 他什么都不知道
Oh, he don't know nothing.
他的脑浆还溅到了桌子上
His brains is under the end table.
他什么都没法告诉我们 迈克
He can't tell us shit, Mike.
- 他全搞砸了 - 你什么意思？
- He's all fucked up. - What's your point?
死掉的嫌犯什么都不会说的
Dead suspects can't say shit.
看起来活着的也什么都不说 那我只能把这哥们儿解决了
It seems like live suspects don't say shit either, so I'll hot this dude here.
- 还能把收监手续都免了 - 我什么都不知道
- Save us the paperwork. - I don't know nothing!
我可该死的不是做什么监视的工作的 是他做的
I don't do motherfucking surveillance, man. He do surveillance.
他不让任何人碰他的录影机
He don't let nobody touch his camera.
- 那录影机里有什么？- 枪手迈克 行动又开始了
- What's on that camera? - Trigger Mike strikes again.
嗨 欢迎来派特音像店 有什么可以效劳的吗？
Hi, welcome to Phat's. How can I help you?
- 迈阿密警察 - 哇 警察啊 我喜欢那场表演
- Miami PD. - Whoa. Cops. I love that show.
- 我们必须看看这录影带里有什么 - 当然可以
- We need to see what's on this video. - Absolutely.
那里有个小弹孔 你们能告诉我那是怎么回事吗？
You got a little bullet hole in there. You guys tell me about it?
我猜不行 我会把这个放在 我们的测试机器里
Guess not. We'll put this in our central floor model.
它的低音很强劲 你喜欢嘻哈音乐吗？我可很喜欢
It has kick- ass bass. You like hip-hop? I love it.
我们在休息室里面可以随意表演
We freestyle in the break room.
你们会玩什么动作 我们都能模仿出来
If you guys ever want to kick it, we'll flow.
投到宽银幕上 比例正确
We're gonna set you up on the wide-screen. Correct ratio.
好了 开始了
There you go.
西班牙棕榈殡仪馆
Spanish Palms Mortuary.
为什么他们要监视殡仪馆？
Why would they be doing surveillance at a funeral home?
那是面古巴国旗吗？
Is that a Cuban flag?
那里 看见那枪了吗？
Right there. See the gun?
从没见过殡仪馆的人还要带武器的
Never knew guards at funeral homes needed to carry them kind of weapons.
看起来我们该把它关上了
It just seems like we should turn it off…
因为这商店是我老爸的
because my dad owns the store.
她有个舌环
She got a tongue ring.
- 像个色情录影带 我们不 - 伙计 伙计
- This is like a porno. We're not… - Dude. Dude.
- 行吗？- 好吧
- All right? - Yeah.
很好 很好
Okay. Okay.
只是 你知道 我的老爸就要
It's just, you know, my dad's gonna be…
我必须 我想我
I just need to… I think I…
- 我想我把这事搞砸了 - 放松点
- I think I screwed this up. - Relax.
- 我老爸会 这像个色情电影 - 哦 我还要
- My dad's gonna… This is like a porno. - Oh, yeah. I want more.
- 好的 - 我们在执行公务
- Okay. - This is official police business.
- 这里该死的是怎么回事？- 让开
- What the fuck's going on here? - Out of my way.
我老爸来了 我老爸来了
My dad is coming. My dad is coming.
你在我店里搞什么？
What the hell is going on in my store?
儿子 这出现在我店里的 色情垃圾是怎么回事
Son, how did this porno crap get on my videos in my store?!
这儿该死的都发生了些什么
What the hell is going on in here?!
- 你还好吗？- 不 我感觉不太好 迈克
- You all right? - No, I'm not all right, Mike.
这破事儿已经缠了我三天了 我的神经都出毛病了
Three days of this shit. Got my nerves all rattled.
我的屁股还在疼
My ass still hurts…
自从那天晚上你做了那好事以后
from what you did to it the other night.
哦 我的上帝
Oh, my Lord.
是的 越来越糟糕了
Yeah, it got rough.
你知道吗？
You know?
我的意思是 我们正巧碰上这些破事儿 事情变得不可收拾
I mean, we got caught up in the moment, shit got crazy.
你知道我的感觉
You know how I get.
当你在后面给了我一下 我想你伤到了我的一些神经
When you popped me from behind, I think you damaged some nerves.
是嘛
Okay.
现在 我不能
Now, I can't…
我不能 现在 我不能
I can't. Now, I can't…
- 不能什么？- 我甚至不能勃起了
- Can't what? - I can't even get an erection.
勃起是什么意思？
What's an erection?
我尝试过服用伟哥 你知道 一颗 两颗
I tried taking Viagra, you know, pop one, pop two.
就像糖果一样把它们吃下去
Been eating them like Skittles.
那可怜的人真是把心都掏出来了
That poor man is pouring out his heart.
而我还是软塌塌的
And I'm still flaccid.
好吧 我很高兴能和你聊
Okay. I'm comfortable talking to you…
这是杜比 5.1 声道的
It's got 5.1 Dolby.
关于我对你的屁股所做的事
about what I did to your ass…
可是你无法勃起
but you not getting an erection…
那确实是个大问题
that's a reaI problem for me.
- 我只是觉得也许可以和你谈谈这事 - 是的 哦 不不
- I just figured I could talk to you. - Yeah. No, no.
我们是 我们是拍档 可我们还得保持适当的距离
We're… We partners, but we are partners with boundaries.
我们之间有个新规定
We got a new rule.
从现在起 你不能对我说「疲软」这个词
From now on you can't say the word "flaccid" to me.
他真是个卑鄙的家伙
He's a mean fuck.
看这儿 这是我们的禁语盒子
Look here. This is our little boundary box.
现在我们要把「疲软」这个词
So we gonna take the word "flaccid"…
我们要把它 和我老妈的「奶」都放进去
and we're gonna put it in there with my mom's titties…
还有你的勃起问题 然后我们要把这盒子关上
with your erection problems, and we're gonna close this box…
然后我们把这破玩意扔进海里
and we're gonna throw this bitch in the ocean.
而你能拿到这盒子的唯一方法
And the only way that you can get to this box…
就是你成为那个叫雅克·库斯托的该死的探险家
is you got to be motherfucking Jacques Cousteau.
我们很酷吧？
We cool?
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
你们怎么可以在我的孩子面前
In front of my babies
放那些个又是色情又是同性恋的片子
you got porno and homo shows up in here?
这是个什么变态商店
What kind of freak-ass store is this?
你们这两个变态 需要上帝来拯救你们
And you two motherfuckers need Jesus.
把耳朵掩上 孩子们
Cover your ears, baby.
棕榈殡仪馆 属于一家离岸控股公司
Palm Mortuary, owned by an offshore holding company…
在经过十七次转手后
which, after 17 layers of bullshit…
它转到了 唐娜·玛利亚·塔皮亚的名下
turns out to be registered to Donna Maria Tapia…
她儿子叫胡安·卡洛斯·塔皮亚 他称自己为强尼
mother of Hector Juan Carlos Tapia, who calls himself Johnny.
强尼·塔皮亚 该死
Johnny Tapia. Shit.
每次警察逮捕他以后
Every time the PD goes after him…
他都会反过来指控警员非法拘禁 并且 每次他都赢了
he sues for wrongful arrest. And, oh, does he win.
去年他还获得了九百万美元的赔偿
Last year he was awarded $9 million.
还让好多像你们一样的蠢货警员丢了饭碗
And got a dozen dumb- ass officers like you fired.
不过 他还没有和我们打过交道
Well, he hasn't run across us yet.
我们希望能听到他们在那房子里都说了什么
We'd love to hear what's going on in that house.
用用你的计算机脑袋 窃听他们的电话
Use your computer brain and tap the phone.
没有法官允许 那可是严重违法的
Well, that happens to be highly illegal without a judge.
你就当我们是在进行演习吧
We were thinking of something more along the lines of a training operation.
不 我不能那么做
No, I can't do that.
- 我给你热门球队的球票 - 我想要靠近场边的位置
- Get you tickets to the Heat game. - I need floor seats.
戴着那么厚的镜片 你不需要坐在前排
With thick- ass glasses you don't need floor seats.
他在停车场里就能看见比赛
He can see the game from the parking lot.
这样的条件恐怕我没法帮你们了
I can't work under these conditions.
好吧 热门球队比赛的前排位置 给你了
Floor seats to the Heat. You got it.
- 要湖人队的 - 好吧 湖人的
- Lakers. - Yes, Lakers.
成交 现在就看我的吧
Okay. Watch me work.
喂？是害虫防治中心吗？
Hello? Is this the pest control?
是的 我们有个很讨厌的问题
Yeah. We got a fucking problem.
你知道我们住在哪儿吗？
You know where we live.
- 是的 南迈阿密 - 明白了
- Yeah, South Miami. - We got it.
我们去
Got our way in.
- 非法的？- 你应该换一种说法
- lllegally? - You got to put a word to it.
比如说 秘密的
It's like, secret.
那么 你们想去杀蟑螂？
So y'all want to kill roaches?
- 还是非法的 - 我们要放些监控装置
- lllegal. - We'll plant a couple gypsy wires…
看看塔皮亚都在干些什么勾当
find out what Tapia's up to.
这些是常见的家庭害虫
These are your basic household bugs.
伙计 我们就这么干
Dog, this is what we do.
- 喷药器是拿来干嘛的？- 喷蟑螂的
- What's the sprayers for? - The roaches.
- 蟑螂？可我们是鼠害 - 什么？
- Roaches? We got rats. - Say what?
没问题 小菜一碟
That's not an issue. We can handle that.
我们只要稍微调整一下步骤就行
We'll just have to slightly adjust our approach a little bit.
不 不 我可不和老鼠打交道
Nope. Nope. I don't mess with no rats.
嗨 住口
Hey. Stop it.
我们已经来了 你最好放聪明点
We're in. Get your head right.
迈克 我的屁股已经成年了
Mike, I'm a grown- ass man.
那就夹紧你的 成年屁股 我们开始干活
Get your grown-ass self together and let's do this.
- 您的房子真不错 先生 - 哦 瞧瞧啊
- You got a beautiful house, sir. - Well, start looking.
他们到处都是
They're all over.
那些不是普通的老鼠
Those ain't normal rats.
他的意思是 他们显然是个特殊品种
What he means is that they're obviously a special breed.
- 什么品种？- 婊子养的
- What kind of breed are they? - Big motherfuckers.
干掉这些老鼠并不成问题
Disposing of the rats isn't a problem.
但我们必须确定 房子里没有别的老鼠窝了
But we should ensure there's no breeding elsewhere in the house.
是的 在祖克公司
Yeah, at Zook…
我们喜欢从里到外彻底地检查清楚
we like to work from the outside in, you know.
所以我们准备留下这些 对不起
So we gonna leave these… Excuse me.
我们要把这些留在这里 然后派进一个特别小队
We'll leave these here and send in a special unit.
最好先让我们从其他地方开始
It'd be better to begin in the rest of the house.
你们不能进入房子里的其他地方
You're not getting in the rest of the house.
那我们将不能保证我们的工作效果
We won't be able to guarantee our work.
我们可以担保的唯一事情
The only thing that we can guarantee…
是这些老鼠会继续做爱
is that these rats will keep fucking.
不断繁殖后代 除非我们找到他们的殖民地
Giving off offspring until we find the colony.
老鼠不会搞什么殖民地
Rats don't got no stinking colony.
哦 事实上 这些是 殖民鼠
Well, actually these are colonial rats.
他们会派出那些工作鼠 被称为
What they do is they send out worker rats that are called…
负鼠
Marsupials.
知道吗 这些雄鼠 他们是鼠世界的开拓者
These drones, they're explorers of the rat world, you know.
他们到处找母老鼠
They just looking for rat pussy.
- 你应该知道的 - 你想耍我吗？
- You know. - Are you fucking with me?
等等 是你叫我们来的 我们可以现在就走 没问题的
Hold on. You called us. We can leave.
可你要明白 这些老鼠每天会做爱两次
But what you should understand is that these rats will hump twice a day.
好吧 从那儿下楼 把它们全杀了 然后把帐单给我
All right. Down there. Just kill them and bring me the bill.
该死 我们说了些什么啊 我们在这儿说了堆屁话
That's that bulIshit. That's that bullshit right there.
- 你看见这些老鼠了吗？- 快埋线吧
- You see these rats? - Plant your wires.
你不是要把我一个人留在这堆老鼠里吧
You're not leaving me with them.
放你的窃听器吧
Plant your wires.
先生们 阿力克斯 约瑟夫
Gentlemen. Alexei, Josef.
哦 我真喜欢你这么称呼 强尼 先生们
Oh, I really like that word, Johnny."Gentlemen."
我不过想表现得礼貌些 这是谈生意 我们大可放松
I'm just trying being civil. This is business, we can all relax.
- 阿力克斯 你想来支雪茄？- 为什么不呢？
- Alexei, would you like a Cohiba? - Why not?
太棒了 你呢？约瑟夫？
Of course. And you? Josef.
我听说你是个品酒行家
I'm told you're a wine connoisseur.
可以这么说
I am.
卡洛斯 让约瑟夫挑瓶酒
Carlos, have Josef pick a wine
再给阿力克斯和我一人来支雪茄 来吧
and Alexei and I will have a cigar. Come.
- 你该死的要去哪儿？- 你这儿问题很严重
- Where the fuck you going? - Pretty bad problem you got here.
我要回卡车一趟 去拿点毒药之类的
I'm gonna head down to the truck, get some poison pellets and stuff.
快去快回 别到处乱转
Come straight back. No screwing around.
他们到处都是
They're all over.
你这儿真不错
Nice place you got here.
这房子是我母亲的 已建成几百万年了
It's Mama's. And it's a shit hole. Built a fucking million years ago.
- 昂贵的老房子 对吧？- 哦 不
- Expensive shithole, eh? - Oh, no.
我在古巴建了所新房子 那可是间大房子 我的兄弟
My new place I'm building in Cuba. Esto va a set tremendo, brother.
快完工了 所有东西全都是新的 到楼上来吧
Almost finished. Everything fucking shiny new. Come on upstairs.
哦 天
Oh, shit.
哦 真他妈恶心 看那母鼠身上的卵子
Oh, shit! Look at the balls on that motherfucker.
罗伯特
Roberto…
- 办公室里的摄影机出问题了 - 房间里的每件东西都坏了
- the general's office camera is out. - Everything in this house is broken.
我把窃听器藏好了
My wire's planted.
- 你的呢？- 第三个就快装好了
- How about yours? - Almost got three wires planted.
迈克
Mike!
这儿有只公老鼠正在操一只母老鼠
There's a papa rat humping the shit out of this mama rat.
天 他让她不停地淫叫
No, he's straight pile-driving her!
这事儿对我完成任务有帮助吗？
Now, how is that information gonna help me do my job?
它们做起来简直就跟我们一样
They fuck just like us.
杀虫的人在哪儿？
Where's the pest guy?
这下面有情况
There's something going on down here.
该死的老鼠
Goddamn rats.
是的 它们到处都是 就像蟑螂一样
Yeah, they everywhere. Just like cockroaches.
不是我不尊重你
No disrespect…
只是在我拍档没回来之前 我不想谈生意
but I do not wish to talk business until my partner return.
这真让人困惑
It's baffling.
你已经私自决定扣我的钱 还在这儿跟我讲什么尊重？
You secretly decide to pay me less and you talk about respect?
我们还是先等等约瑟夫吧 你知道 我对数字的事可一窍不通
Let's wait for Josef. You know, me and digits.
卡洛斯 你能带约瑟夫进来吗？
Carlos, could you bring Josef in?
好了
So…
你的拍档来了
your partner is here.
现在我们可以开始谈了吧？
Would you like to talk now?
卡洛斯 另一个盒子
Carlos, another box.
现在 你得签个字
So you sign over ownership papers
把你在佛罗里达所有的俱乐部转让给我
for all the Florida clubs you own…
由我来掌管一切事务
and I will control everything…
从货源到销售 怎么样？
from point of origin to sale. Okay?
不要中间人 特别是俄罗斯人
No middleman. Especially Russian middleman.
我非常尊敬你 塔皮亚先生
With all due respect, Mr. Tapia…
在我的国家 我经常看到这样的事发生
in my country, I see such things all the time.
我真为你的国家感到遗憾
I'm sorry for your country.
这肯定是些愚蠢的古巴习俗 把他们放在薄饼箱里
That must be some Cuban stupid tradition to put them in a tortilla bin.
现在 听我说 你这俄国佬
Now, listen to me, you Russian punk.
我 强尼·塔皮亚 会把你的头切下来
l, me, Johnny Tapia, will sever your head off!
如果你杀了我 就会引火上身
You kill me and you will have a shit-storm.
那我是不是该干了你那年轻的妻子
Should I screw your young wife…
或者拜访一下你的儿子 那个足球明星？
or visit your son, the soccer player?
我女儿认识你的儿子
My daughter knows your son.
- 你会后悔的 - 我希望我们还是朋友
- You're gonna regret this. - I hope that we can remain friends.
因为到最后 我们之间只剩下了友谊 信任
Because at the end, what eIse do we have but friendship, trust…
和真诚
honor.
没有这些 我们和禽兽无异
Without this, we are no more than beasts.
厨房的监视器看不清了
The kitchen monitor's out.
外面该死的到底出了什么问题？
What the hell's going on out there?
哦 上帝啊
Shit.
我找到些东西
I found something.
- 是个人的手指 - 什么？难道老鼠把他其余的肉都啃光了？
- It's a guy's finger. - What, did the rats eat the rest of him?
- 你该死的在这儿干嘛？- 嗨 我正要找你呢
- What the fuck are you doing? - Hey, I was just looking for you.
我想我知道你们的问题出在哪儿了
I think I figured out your problem.
你们都是帮肮脏卑鄙下流的家伙
Y'all a bunch of filthy motherfuckers.
快撤
Blow out!
- 怎么回事？该死 - 快离开这房子
- What's going on? Shit! - Get out of the house!
这破事也该结束了
This shit's got to stop.
操
Fuck!
我们该走了
We should go.
快走 快
Go! Go!
和麦克劳瑞共事的又一天开始了
Just another day with Mike Lowrey.
- 该死 走 - 来吧 快啊
- Damn! Go! - Come on!
罗伯托认为 他们就是那两个人
Roberto thinks they were the gangbangers…
上次试图抢我们钱的混蛋 老板
that tried to hijack the drop, boss.
这是怎么回事儿？
How did this thing happen?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我们打电话给捕鼠公司 然后这两个家伙就出现了
We called the rat people and these guys showed up.
也许你就是那只老鼠 嗯？
Maybe you're the rat, huh?
他们试图来偷我的东西
They tried to steal from me,
而你们竟然让他们闯进了我妈的房子
and you let them into my mother's house.
强尼 嗨 不
Johnny. Hey, no.
我永远不会
I would never…
任何人也不能让我的女儿 我的母亲
Nobody puts in danger my daughter, my mother…
还有我的钱陷入危险
or my money.
把他送到殡仪馆去
Send him to the mortuary.
强尼 强尼 罗伯托怎么了？
Johnny. Johnny, what happened to Roberto?
他自杀了 妈妈
He killed himself, Mama.
- 我很难过 - 给他妈妈写封信安慰下吧
- Very sad. - Write a nice letter to his mother.
我会的
I'll do it.
好的 再见
Okay. Bye.
- 你 给他录指纹 - 嗨 麦克 别玩了 伙计
- Yo, run the print. - Mike, stop playing, man!
- 去录指纹 - 别拿那该死的死人手指碰我
- Run the print. - Don't touch me with no dead finger.
劳驾 录一下指纹 我必须查到这是谁的
Excuse me, run this print. I need to find the owner.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想你应该能在这些碎纸上 找到些线索吧？
Think you can find out what's on these shreds?
当然
Of course.
我们正在考虑叫午餐外卖
We're thinking about ordering lunch.
要我们给你们带点脆薄饼和葡萄苏打水吗？
Should we put you down for some extra crispy and a couple of grape sodas?
几杯葡萄苏打水
"Couple of grape sodas."
- 非常有趣 真好笑 - 那不是低潮吗？
- Very funny. That's hilarious. - Isn't it low tide?
我想是的
I think it is.
- 你不是有些亲戚要接送吗？- 什么？
- Don't you have relatives to pick up? - What?
你 你这可是有点过分了 伙计 不 那可不好笑
Yo, now you crossed the line, man. Okay, no, that's not funny.
我们没和你们开玩笑
We're fucking with you.
听着 我们装了些窃听器 需要你们的帮助 不开玩笑的
We planted wires, we need some help. No bullshit.
我要你们
I want you…
查出
to find out…
这两个黑鬼他妈到底是谁
who those two black puta de mierda are.
我要他们躺在这儿
And I want them lying right here…
在我妈的花园里 在这些棺材里
in Mama's garden in these coffins!
我们的神秘手指属于
And our mystery finger belongs to:
约瑟夫·卡尼斯科维奇
Josef Kuninskavich.
他曾是一个俄罗斯黑帮的头
He was a lieutenant in a Russian mob.
拥有几十个佛罗里达的夜总会
Owned a couple dozen Florida nightclubs.
塔皮亚正开始消灭俄罗斯帮派的头目们
Tapia's starting to knock off Russian mob bosses.
来看这些
Got something.
你查到了什么 傻鸟？
What you got, dickhead?
电脑匹配半色调 灰度和饱和度
The computer matches half tones, gray tones, densities.
这是个视频解码器
Sort of like a visual code-breaking.
我把那些碎片拼起来了
Little something I put together.
那些碎纸片是幅照片 像是艘船 迪克西七号
The shredded papers was a photo. Some kind of boat."Dixie 7."
迪克西七号
Dixie 7.
- 它注册在一个叫佛洛德·波蒂的名下 - 波蒂兄弟
- It's registered to a one Floyd Poteet. - The Poteet brothers.
上次那些三K党里的一个
One of the KKK guys we busted.
你把他的耳朵打烂了 还记得吗？
You blew his ear off, remember?
麦克 你能教我怎么开枪打人吗？
Mike, can you teach me how to shoot people?
听听我们在塔皮亚家搜集到的声音
Listen to what we got at Tapia's.
他的副手正在说话
The second-in-command is talking.
他在说 是的 老板 我们找到了一群肥雌兔
He's telling him, "Yes, boss. We found a bunch of fat doe fuckers…
- 我们已经筛选好了 - 筛选肥雌兔？
- and we're getting them emptied." - Fat does emptied?
- 那该死的是什么意思？- 他今天下午有个约会
- The hell does that mean? - He has a meeting this afternoon.
- 知道我是谁吗？- 名字听起来很熟
- You know who I am? - Name sounds familiar.
有幽默感 我喜欢
Sense of humor. I like that.
我们两点在沙滩上见 海岸俱乐部
Meet me on the sand, 2:00, Shore Club.
- 她不知道自己在干嘛 我们开始行动吧 - 你们都跟我来
- She has no idea. Let's roll. - Y'all come with us.
我叫了两杯巴卡第莫希多鸡尾酒
I ordered a couple of Bacardi Mojitos.
迈阿密
Miami.
好的 画面九放大 再来点声音
Okay, zoom in on nine. A little more audio, please.
我们何不游个泳？凉快一下
So, why don't we take a swim? Cool off.
要不我们就待在这儿喝个酩酊大醉 怎么样？
Or we could just stay here and get drunk. How about that?
我们晚点再喝也不迟
Or we could drink this later.
除非你有另有原因
Unless you have a reason…
为何不想弄湿你那性感的身体
why you don't want to get that beautiful body of yours wet.
为何不干脆问我是不是戴了窃听器？
Why not just ask if I'm wearing a wire?
我宁愿去游泳
I'd rather go swimming.
- 他到底在干嘛？- 狗娘养的
- What the hell's he doing? - Son of a bitch.
该死 他要带她下水
Shit. He's taking her into the water.
这家伙很聪明
This guy's smart.
我要你替我工作 何必浪费时间在这里无谓的谈话呢？
I want you to work for me. Why waste time on this unnecessary talking?
当然没必要 你需要另一名银行家做什么？
It's very unnecessary. What do you need with another banker?
和你前雇主的理由一样
For the same reason as your previous employer.
但现在 我拥有所有的俄国俱乐部 没有中间人
But now I own all the Russian clubs. No middleman.
我将成为北美最大的毒品进口商和分销商
I'm about to be the biggest importer and distributor of X in North America.
你会成为非常有钱的年轻富婆 所以我想
You're gonna be a very rich young woman. That's why I thought…
我知道你在想什么 塔皮亚先生
I know what you thought, Mr. Tapia.
只要你没有顾虑
As long as you don't think it more than once…
我很乐意和你一块儿干
I'm happy to be in business with you.
好吧
All right.
我们来做生意吧
Let's do business.
你是警察还是模特儿？
What are you, a cop or a model?
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
随便穿穿而已 我喜欢打扮得漂亮点 怎么啦？
I threw something on. I like looking good. What?
给谁看啊？
For who?
别恨对手 恨比赛吧
Don't hate the player. Hate the game.
我恨那裁缝
I hate the tailor.
干得好 我们会抓住他的
Good job. We'll get him.
你哥想跟你谈一谈 在对面
Your brother would love to talk to you down the street.
怎么回事？
Whoa, what's going on?
你想毁了我的案子 还是你疯了？
You trying to blow my case or you just insane?
你才是在和古巴疯子打交道
You're the one taking a dip with the Cubano maniac.
- 你怎么知道的？- 我们在房子里装了窃听器
- How'd you know that? - We had a wire in the house.
- 你们俩有权利在那安装窃听器？- 听着 去它的 好吗？
- You two have a warrant for that wire? - Look, fuck that, okay?
你不知道你身处何种险境 西德妮
You don't know the kind of danger that you're in, Syd.
我完全明白 而且我完全有能力办好我所做的事
I am fully aware and I am fully capable of what I am doing.
我不再是你的小妹妹了
I am not your baby sister anymore.
对缉毒组来说 你仅仅是个花瓶
For the DEA you ain't nothing but a honeypot.
你刚说什么？
What'd you just say?
所以你才得到了这份工作 因为你穿起泳装来身材很惹火
That's why you got the job, because you look good in a bathing suit.
好吧 我们找个地方坐下来谈吧
All right, let's sit down somewhere.
好了 听着 西德妮 有些事你必须要了解
All right, look, Syd, there's some shit you need to know.
强尼·塔皮亚在他妈妈的厨房里 剁了俄罗斯的黑帮老大
Johnny Tapia is cutting up Russian mob bosses in his mom's kitchen.
在厨房里 西德妮
In the kitchen, Syd.
他在锅子旁边找到了一截手指
He found a severed finger by the crock pot.
你将卷入一场毒品恶战
You're about to be in the middle of a drug war.
迈阿密警探已抓过这家伙十二次 但每次都苦无罪证
Miami PD has arrested this guy 12 times with no convictions.
你们何不歇手 让我们来缉捕他？
Why don't you just hang back and let us bring him down?
伙计们 听着 我需要这案子 好吗？我已经很接近了
Guys, look, I need this, okay? And I am this close.
怎么个接近法？
What's "this close"?
在他整个行动中 我负责洗钱
I'm in charge of money laundering for his entire operation.
一两个月内 我们就能搜集到足够的罪证 然后他就完蛋了
ln a month or two we'll have enough for a conviction and it'll be over.
一两天怎么样？听起来更好吧？
What about a day or two? Sound better?
马库斯和我认为 我们发现了塔皮亚整个计划中的关键
Marcus and I think we found the key to Tapia's whole operation.
你现在无话可说了吧？
You have nothing to say now, huh?
- 很惊讶 对吧？- 好了 别闹了 你们俩 可恶
- Just stuck, right? - Okay, time-out, y'all. Damn.
我们找到了个家伙
We got this peckerwood that'll put us down…
他知道塔皮亚的货最终被运到哪儿 你想加入吗？
with the transport end of Tapia's operation. Do you want in?
- 你怎么可以？- 什么时候？
- Why would you… - When?
- 今晚 - 到时叫我
- Tonight. - Page me.
我该带我的皮带吗？
Should I bring my thong?
把你的脏手放开 我会打得你屁滚尿流
Get your bitch hands off. I'll knock you the fuck out.
迈克 我们想办法让她脱身
Mike, we're trying to keep her out of trouble, man…
而不是邀她加入
not invite her in.
伙计 我刚想清楚了 你知道 如果她跟着我们
Man, I just figured, you know, if she with us…
至少麻烦会比较少些
that's just less trouble she could get into.
我也要跟你说清楚 伙计 我想她自己能照顾自己了
I'm gonna keep it reaI with you too, man. I think she can handle herself.
我也跟你说清楚 没有人比我更了解我妹了
I'm gonna keep it reaI with you. Don't nobody know my sister like I do.
知道吗？她没做出正确的选择 迈克
Okay? She doesn't make good choices, Mike.
- 她不是那种很机灵的人 - 没能做出正确的选择？
- She's not street-smart. - Doesn't make good…
- 哪种选择？- 比如男人 就是其中一项
- Like, what kind of choices? - Men, for one.
她迷上了这些蠢人
She's attracted to these dumb…
那些只有大块肌肉的猪头 迈克 你明白吗？
flashy, just musclebound dickheads, Mike. You know?
那帮该死的混蛋们 甚至都没法转身擦自己屁股
Cock diesel motherfuckers that can't even fucking turn to wipe their ass.
- 懂我意思吗？- 是的
- You feel me? - Yeah.
你知道吗？他们笨得跟一桶虾似的
You know? Just dumb as a bucket of shrimp.
对对 那样是够
Yeah. Yeah. That shit's crazy.
我是说 你不觉得 也许你
I mean, you don't think maybe you…
也许你没有 比如说 没有机会好好认识他们一下？
Maybe you didn't, like, get a chance to know any of them?
我会给下一个人一次机会
I'm gonna give the next one a chance.
给他一次抓屁股的机会
A chance to whup his ass.
- 叫他把屎挖出来 - 你想跟他打架吗？
- Whup the shit out of him. - Oh, you gonna fight him?
我要做的肯定是非法的
What I'm gonna do ain't even gonna be legal.
然后可能会被关在这儿 跟这些混蛋在一起
I might be up in here with these motherfuckers.
你懂我的意思吗？
Do you know what I mean?
你该死的看什么看？
The fuck you looking at?
太感谢你了
谢谢
Thank you kindly.
- 谁保释我出来的？- 嗨 佛洛德表弟
- Who sprung me? - Hey, Cousin Floyd.
- 哦 是你 - 记得我吗？
- Oh, you. - Remember me?
笑一个
Cheese.
你俩合照样子真不错
Y'all look great together.
- 你们到底想干嘛？- 只是需要你帮你一点点忙
- What the fuck you doing? - Just a little insurance.
你要帮我们找出迪克西七号
You gonna help us find Dixie 7…
告诉我们那艘船和强尼·塔皮亚有什么关系
and tell us what that boat has to do with Johnny Tapia.
- 我可不是内奸 - 哦 你不是内奸？
- I ain't no snitch. - Oh, you ain't no snitch?
- 哦 糟糕 真遗憾 - 知道我会怎么做吗？
- Oh, damn. That's a shame. - Know what I'm gonna do?
我会寄张特大的8×10寸照给他监狱里的3K党弟兄
I'm gonna send a special 8 x 10 to his KKK buddies back in jail.
你知道吗？这还是数码相片
You know what, it's a digital photo too.
所以 我们想怎么改就怎么改
So we can do whatever we want to do with it.
等我们弄好之后
By the time we get done with you…
你会出现在巴斯塔·莱姆斯的下一个音乐录影带里
you gonna be in the next Busta Rhymes video on BET.
进去吧
Tuck ass.
我可是有人权的
I got my rights.
我很担心 迈阿密方面动作频繁
I'm worried. There's too much heat around in Miami.
我感觉的出来 感觉的出来
I can feel it. I can feel it.
我们得尽快把钱装进棺材 运往古巴
We need to put my money in coffins to Cuba faster.
你叫停尸房那边加快速度 好吗？
You should tell the mortuary to speed things up. All right?
外面那个是水道标记
That's the channel marker way out there.
他们大多在天亮时下货 但今晚有一趟
They make the drop mostly at dawn, but there'll be one today, though.
西德妮 你跟有没有跟妈妈联系过？她患了荨麻疹
Syd, you talk to Mama? She's got hives.
哦 我还告诉了妈妈 你古巴男友的事
Oh, and I told Mama about your Cubano boyfriend.
她想请他来吃圣诞晚餐
He ain't invited to Christmas dinner.
换个电台吧 多一点音乐 少一点马克斯
Change the station. More music, less Marcus.
只要你一回话 接下来的四十分钟 他便会说个没完没了
If you open the door he'll be a black Dr. Phil for the next 40 minutes.
西德妮 你最好别跟迈克太亲热
Syd, you might not want to get too flirty with Mike.
你男朋友可能会切掉他的食指
Your boyfriend might cut off his trigger finger.
也许迈克一直在跟我拍拖 你有想过吗？
Maybe Mike's been flirting with me. Did you ever think about that?
摧花手迈克？
Trigger Mike?
不 别这样 别玩那小子
Not like this. Don't play with that boy.
- 我是认真的 别玩那小子 - 告诉他纽约的事
- Seriously. Don't play with that boy. - Just tell him about New York.
- 说啊 - 告诉我什么？
- Do it. - Tell me what?
哦 糟糕 他下台阶了吗？
Oh, shit. Is he walking down the steps?
糟糕 他下来了
Oh, shit. He coming down.
- 没事的 - 对 你真的搞砸了
- It's okay. - Yeah, you done fucked up.
这回你可真的搞砸了
You done fucked up.
你记得
You remember…
记得我去过纽约吧？记得吗？
Remember I went to New York? You remember?
还有
And…
我说过 西德妮
I said, "Syd."
我碰到
I ran in…
是西德妮碰到了我 就在纽约的某条大街上
Syd ran into me in New York on the street in that place.
然后我说
And I said:
你好
"What's up?"
我们那时饿了 所以后来
And we was hungry, so then…
她吃了点鱼
she had fish.
是鲈鱼
It was grouper.
然后我吃了点鸡肉
And then I had some chicken.
记得我本该回家的吗？
Remember I was supposed to come home?
但我没有
But I didn't.
我们出去约会了
We went out on a date.
实际上是五次 现在我们又能见面了
Five, actually. Now we're seeing each other.
等等
Hold up.
你知道的 我真的很尊重你 马库斯 什么事也没发生过
You know, really out of respect for you, Marcus, nothing happened.
嗨 迈克 你为何拐弯抹角呢？
Hey, Mike, why you tripping, man?
我意思是 我们得先确定 你能冷静面对这事
I mean, we wanted to make sure you was cool with it.
要知道 我怎么想并不重要
Doesn't matter what I think, you know.
嗨 可我必须得这样发现你们的关系吗？
Hey, I had to find out like this, right?
没关系
Don't matter.
让我问你 你们要生小孩吗？一小堆迷你迈克？
Let me ask you, y'all gonna have babies? Little bunch of mini Mikes?
一堆只会撒谎 暴力的小混蛋吗？
Bunch of little lying, violent motherfuckers?
马库斯 什么也没发生过
Marcus, nothing happened.
我只想说 妈妈一定会吓一跳的
I just want to say, Mama's gonna be thrilled.
好了 你知道吗？你得来点放松 或别的什么
All right, you know what, you need to "whoosah" or something for a second.
嗨 迪克西七号来了
Hey, here comes the Dixie 7.
迈克 别理他
Just leave it alone.
- 你干嘛那样子？- 不关你的事
- Why you acting like that? - Go on about your business, man.
- 我们得谈谈这件事 - 不 不 别挡在我面前
- We gonna talk about this. - No. Get out of my face.
- 我一直想跟你谈 - 你放开我 迈克
- I'm trying to talk to you. - Get the fuck off me, Mike.
你该死的到底有啥毛病 啊？你干嘛总表现得那么愚蠢？
What the hell is your problem, man?! Why you acting so stupid?!
是因为这糟糕的搭档关系 所以我才表现的那样
This is a dysfunctionaI partnership. That's why I'm acting like that.
- 你知道 - 我们之间缺乏信任 迈克
- You know - There ain't no trust.
我没骗你
I didn't lie to you!
我一直在等待合适的时机告诉你 可那不是你的问题
I was waiting for the right time to tell you. But that ain't your issue.
你何不挑明对我说 你对这事儿有何不满？
Why don't you bring it to me real. What is your problem with this?!
知道吗 伙计？你是条狗
You know what? You a dog, man.
- 没错 是的 我说了 - 哦 好的
- That's it. There it is. I said it. - Oh, okay.
你就像条发情的公狗 脑子里都是那样的东西 迈克
You like a pit bull with that little pink thing hanging out.
原来是这样 哦 我明白了
Oh, it's like that. Oh, okay.
我配不上你老妹
I'm not good enough for your sister.
你们俩够了 船来了
Guys, enough. The boat's coming.
好吧 我们会解决那事的 继续干活吧 老兄
Okay. We gonna handle that shit. Go ahead, man.
大约一小时内 投货的船就会来
ln about an hour, the drop boat's gonna come.
看到他们了
We got them.
不知道那棺材会运往哪间停尸房
Wonder what mortuary that coffin's going to.
笔直开过去
Keep going straight by.
看到了吧？
You seeing what I'm seeing?
把货送到停尸房 别搞砸了
Get the load to the mortuary and don't screw up.
没问题
I got it.
装货
Load up.
他们要走了
They're getting away!
停车 停车
Stop! Stop!
我们需要用你的车 行吗？
We need your car. All right?
- 不 不 - 你能不能弄辆好点的车？
- Get out the car. - Can't you get a better car than that?
让那人走
Let that man go!
- 别用那种口气对我说话 - 神经病
- Don't be coming at me with that tone. - Freak.
- 小车不会破坏臭氧层 - 那辆才是我要的车
- Small cars don't hurt the ozone layer. - That's what I'm talking about.
- 停车 - 下 对
- Stop the car. - Get Yeah.
- 打开后车厢 出来 你进去 - 下车 下车
- Pop the trunk. Get out. Get in. - Get out. Get out.
- 把你的屁股放进去 - 好的
- Get your ass in. - Okay.
- 我正在卖车呢 - 非得让我掏枪出来吗？
- I am in the middle of a sale. - Do I have to pull my gun?
哦 天啊 丹·马里诺 你好
Oh, shit. Dan Marino. What's up?
退后点 丹 嗨 真的是你吗
Back up, Dan. Hey, you're the truth.
- 要什么只管吩咐 警官 - 那是丹·马里诺
- Whatever you need, officers. - That's Dan Marino.
- 嗨 退后 - 让我试试它的性能到底如何
- Hey. Back up. - Let me know how it rides.
他一定会好好测试的
He's gonna test-drive the shit out this.
去吧 我不想暴露自己的身份
Go. I don't want to blow my cover.
看到了 他们就在那边
Got them. Got them right there.
你干嘛非得开这么近？
Why you gotta get so close?
- 我不会让那棺材脱手的 - 但四周都是他们的人
- I won't let that coffin get away. - But they're all around us.
该死 是那两个黑鬼
Shit, those are the gangbangers.
放松点 他们又不认识我们
Relax, they don't know us.
老板 我们这里出了点状况 我们被人跟踪了
Boss, we got a problem here. We're being followed.
这下麻烦大了 卡洛斯
This is a big problem, Carlos.
- 抱歉 老板 我会处理的 - 宰了那些黑鬼 懂了吗？
- Sorry, boss. I'll take care of it, okay? - Kill those black bitches. All right?!
他们害死我们了 有卧底混进来了
They made us. Get some undercovers to roll with us.
我们分头行驶 大家到伯克斯特 马上
We're splitting up. Everybody go to Third and Boxter, now!
我们行动吧
Here we go.
我可没签生死状要卷入飞车追逐呀
I didn't sign up for no goddamned car chase!
你发疯了吗？
Have you lost your mind?
迈克 我看你一心一意想干蠢事 所以请让我下车
I see you got your mind set on doing dumb shit, so please let me out!
这样的画面我只在电影中见过一次 不过他们没成功
I seen this in a movie once. They didn't make it!
哦 可恶
Oh, shit!
- 当心那卡车 - 没问题
- Dump truck! - I got it.
- 迈克 - 我没事 没事
- Mike! - I'm fine. I'm fine.
那边 该死 迈克
Right there! Oh, shit, Mike!
- 你看到那该死的车了吗？- 不 没有
- Did you see that shit? - No shit.
丹·马里诺绝对该买下这车
Dan Marino should definitely buy this car.
不是这辆 这辆已经快被我撞烂了
Not this one. I'm fucking this one up.
不过绝对要这个款式的车
But definitely one like this.
哦 我们要撞上了 要撞上了
I almost missed that.
好了 差点搞砸了 我差点搞砸了
All right, that was almost fucked up. I almost fucked up.
该死
Shit!
这没必要
This is not necessary.
哦 该死
Oh, shit!
- 该死 - 引擎盖上有个死人 死人
- Damn! - Dead man on the hood! Dead man!
- 我正在想办法甩掉 - 快甩掉
- I'm trying to get it off. - Get it off!
我是在想办法甩掉啊
I'm trying to get it off.
- 那东西真够恶的 太恶心了 - 快甩掉 甩
- That shit's nasty. That's nasty. - Get it off! Get…
那东西太恶心了
That shit is nasty.
- 便衣警察 通通离开 - 便衣警察
- Undercover police! Everybody move! - Undercover police!
- 快走 - 走 走 走
- Move! - Move! Move! Move!
要转弯了
Coming around the corner!
准备 他们快到了 动作快
Get ready, they're coming around the block. Move!
上面
Up top!
该死的
Shit!
这要是我的车 我可就气炸了
Boy, if this was my car, I'd be pissed!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
想打破一周枪战世界纪录吗？
Trying to break the world record for gun fights in a week!?
别在这时候挖苦人
This is not the time to criticize!
你一直在埋怨我 我再也受不了
I can't work with you blaming me all the time!
- 难道这不是你的错？- 不是 不 不
- This is not your fault? - This is not… No! No!
扯蛋 迈克 一切都是你的错
Bullshit, Mike! Everything's your fault!
好的 我们走 快走
Okay, let's go! Let's go!
- 这儿没人了 - 很好
- Clear around! - Cool!
我下去
I'm going around!
- 迈克 逮住他 - 他们把棺材运走了
- Mike, got him! - They got the coffin.
闪开
Move!
闪开 快闪 趴下 警察 都趴下
Move! Move! Get down! Police! Get down!
闪开 快闪开
Move! Move!
警察 闪 闪开
Police! Move! Move!
别挡路 闪 闪开
Get out of my way! Move! Move!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
可恶 开门 警察
Shit! Open the door! Police!
不
No!
哦 该死
Whoa! Shit!
迈克 迈克
Mike! Mike!
那小子咬我
That boy bit me!
迈克
Mike!
让开 让开
Move! Move!
警察 闪开
Police! Move!
他在底下吗？
He under there?
我们追丢了棺材
We lost the coffin…
现在 你还把我们唯一的带路者给烤焦了 迈克
and you barbecued our only lead, Mike.
我当了一辈子警察 这是最惨 最痛苦的一周
This has got to be the worst, most emotional cop week of my life.
对 是有点辛苦
Yeah, it's been a little rough.
- 这些尸体要运到哪去？- 不知道 这真的很奇怪
- Where were these bodies going? - I don't know. It's really strange.
我们发现所有的尸体内部都是空的
All the John Does we found out here are empty.
空的尸体 还都很肥
Empty Does. Fat Does.
切开来 取走器官 再缝合起来
Cut them open, took the organs out. Sewed them back up.
干得漂亮
Nice work.
你们把事情搞得越乱 我们看起来越像摇滚明星
The more you guys fuck up, the more we look like rock stars.
你们追的车子是市立停尸房的车
The van you was chasing is a transport for the city morgue.
尸体要送往大学作医学研究用
The John Does were being delivered to the university for medical research.
- 干得太好了 - 我真不敢相信 伙计们
- Nice going. - I can't believe you guys.
你们俩早上是否有互打电话的习惯？
Do you both wake up in the morning, call each other up?
「早安 马库斯」 「早上好 迈克」
"Good morning, Marcus." "Morning, Mike."
「你好吗？」 「很好」
"How are you doing?" "A'ight."
「那我们今天打算怎样捣毁局长的生活呢？」
"So how are we gonna fuck up the captain's life today?"
「天啊 我不知道」 「我不知道」
"Gee, I don't know." "I don't know."
哦 你看 那边
"Ooh. Look, over there.
我们来杀三个胖子吧
Let's kill three fat people…
再把他们丢在街上
and leave them on the street."
我们压过之前他们早就死了
They were dead before we ran over them.
有没有死并不重要 该死
It doesn't matter whether they were dead or not, goddamn it!
每次你们在街上放个尸体
Every time you leave a corpse on the street…
我就得让这些法医人员来看看怎么回事
I have to get these forensic coroner guys to come to see what happened.
然后我得派调查人员来 瞧见没？他们在调查呢
Then I gotta get detectives. See? They're detecting shit.
然后我还得叫这些人 把尸体装进该死的袋子里
Then I gotta get these forensic guys to stick them back in the fucking bag!
上帝啊
Jesus Christ!
你们两个 你们就像是
You guys, you're like…
就像一群吸血虱子
You're like a bunch of bloodsucking ticks…
吸干局里的生命之血
draining the life's blood out of this department.
去他的 局长
Damn the whoosah, captain.
- 你刚叫我虱子吗？- 我是在说他
- Did you just call me a tick? - I was referring to him.
- 我想是的 - 局长 这些不是正常的尸体
- Thought so. - Captain. These aren't normal corpses.
如果我把你从辆急驰的冷冻货车里扔出去
If I threw you out of a speeding ice truck…
然后再辗过你的头 你也不会正常的
and then ran over your head, you wouldn't be normal either.
你想一想 这些尸体的内脏被掏干净了
Think about this for a second. These bodies have been emptied…
而它们又属于碰巧开了停尸间的毒贩子
from a drug smuggler that just happens to own a mortuary.
要是我有一大堆尸体 里头有很多空间的话
I got a bunch of bodies waiting with plenty of room in them…
我就能走私物品
I could smuggle some shit.
强尼·塔皮亚有着完美的掩护
Johnny Tapia has the perfect cover.
强尼·塔皮亚？
Johnny Tapia?
对 我要立刻拿到搜查令 去搜他的停尸间
I want a warrant to go into his mortuaries immediately.
不不不不 不行 理由呢？理由呢？
No warrant. What? For what? For what?
就因为他们送一堆死人去作医学研究？
For a bunch of dead guys on their way to med research?
不 每次我们追捕他 他总能告赢我们
No. Every time we go after him, he sues us and wins.
这事到此为止 否则他们会炒了我们 解散TNT小组
This shit stops now or they'll fire us, disband TNT…
把我装进该死的棺材
and stick me in a fucking coffin.
- 这事到此为止 - 那「不惜代价」是怎么回事？
- This is over now! - What happened to "whatever it takes"?
那是因为那是场车祸大屠杀 更不用说强尼·塔皮亚
That was pre- vehicular manslaughter. Not to mention Johnny Tapia…
- 那儿到底怎么是了？- 哦 该死
- What the fuck is that? - Oh, shit.
闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up. Shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
嗨 这人侵犯了我的人权
This man has violated my rights!
该死那人又是谁？
Who the fuck is that?
你们压死人还不够吗？现在还扯上绑架？
Running people over is not enough for you? Now you're into kidnapping?
那人是个罪犯 明白吗 局长？我们抓住了他 就在
That man is a criminal. Okay? We busted him at the…
抱歉 我已经快被搞死
Excuse me, I have so much brass up my ass…
可能有人要为我唱国歌了
I could be playing "The Star-Spangled Banner."
我也无能为力了 老兄
I ain't cut out for this, man.
别这样 伙计 我现在不想和你吵架
Come on, man. I can't do this with you right now.
- 我在重新评估什么才更重要 - 关于什么？要不要当警察吗？
- I'm re-evaluating what's important. - About what? Being a cop?
不 是关于你做我搭档的事
No, about you being my partner.
是因为西德妮吗？老天 嗨 马库斯
Is this about Syd? God! Hey, Marcus, man…
那事你做的是不对 但不是因为它 迈克
That was messed up, but that ain't what this is about, Mike.
一旦我们去抓塔皮亚 你我就完了
Once we nail Tapia, you and me, we're over.
我已经签了我的调职书
I already signed my transfer papers.
梅根 带你去看电影的小子叫什么？
Megan, what's the name of this boy taking you to the movies?
雷吉
Reggie.
老爸 拜托你待会儿别问他一大堆问题 而令我难堪
Daddy, please don't embarrass me and ask him a lot of questions.
大家都知道你是警察 这让他们都很紧张
Everybody knows you're a cop, and it makes people nervous.
干嘛紧张？他犯罪了吗？
Well, why nervous? He on crack?
- 没事吧？- 没事 进来吧
- It's cool? - Yeah. Come in.
你怎么？
What'd you…
我获准秘密搜查了
I got a sneak and peek.
辛克莱法官说我们今晚可以去停尸房
Judge Sinclair said we can go into the mortuary tonight.
我们不能碰任何东西 但万一我们找到什么的话
We can't touch nothing, but if we find something…
他给我们开正式的搜查令
he'll give us a righteous warrant.
你总喜欢惹毛霍华德局长 是不是啊？
You love pissing Captain Howard off, don't you?
我是警察
It's what I do.
你几时开始打高尔夫的？
So when you start playing golf?
嗨 你想调职的事是认真的吗？
Hey, so you real serious about this transfer thing, huh?
我是说 你已经十年没干那行了 我刚一直在想
I mean, you been quitting for 10 years. I just always thought it was…
你会怎样来应付那些破事？
how you dealt with all this shit.
那样对我和我的家人来说才最好
It's what's best for me and my family.
现在 我去拿我的东西
Look, I'm gonna get my stuff, man.
一同狂飙 生死与共
"We ride together, we die together.
永远的坏小子们
Bad boys for life."
我们越来越老了 迈克
We getting old, Mike.
有个小子要来约我的宝贝女儿 出去过她的首次约会
One of them young punks coming to take my baby out on her first date.
- 你这混球是谁？- 嗨 伯内特先生 我是雷吉
- Who the fuck are you? - Hi, Mr. Burnett. I'm Reggie.
- 你来做什么？- 我来带梅根出去
- What you doing here? - I came to take out Megan.
- 什么？- 我来带梅根出去
- What?! - I came to take out Megan.
- 你几岁？- 十五岁 伯耐特先生
- How old are you? - I'm 15, Mr. Burnett.
该死 你看起来像三十岁
Motherfucker, you look 30.
- 给我看看你的证件 - 我没带在身上
- Show me some lD. - I don't have none on me.
你没带证件 给我靠墙站好
You don't have no lD. Get your ass up against that wall.
你有何毛病？
What is your problem?
自以为无所不知的小霹雳猫
You think you know it all. Little young Thundercats.
- 身上有大麻吗？- 没有
- Got joints on you? - No.
- 你吸毒吗？- 不 先生
- You smoke that shit? - No, sir.
你打算让我女儿兴奋吗？你有没有吸毒？
You trying to get my daughter high? Do you smoke that shit?
- 老弟 门口那人是谁？- 雷吉
- Nigga, who that is at the door? - It's Reggie.
- 雷吉是谁？- 来带梅根出去的
- Who the fuck is Reggie? - Came to take Megan out.
- 你想干嘛 小子？- 我来带他的女儿出去
- What you want, nigga? - I'm here to take his daughter out.
- 你叫什么？- 雷吉
- What's your name? - Reggie.
我听到这混蛋说你叫雷吉了
I heard the motherfucker say your name Reggie.
你现在要带梅根出去？
You taking Megan out?
- 你几岁了？- 15岁
- How old is you? - Fifteen.
- 该死 小子 你至少有30岁了 - 这位是迈克
- Shit, nigga, you at least 30. - This is Mike.
- 你会打架吗？- 会
- Can you fight? - Yeah.
你会打架？混帐 你会打架 好 我倒要看看
You can fight? Motherfucker. You can't fight. Look at you…
- 别说了 - 我想知道如果
- Cut it out. - I want to know if…
有人要带我的侄女出去 我要知道他会不会打架
When somebody taking my niece out, I want to know if he can fight.
可能有人会过来找麻烦 如果小子不会打架 她就脱不了身
Somebody might come say something, the nigga can't fight, she can't go.
这是梅根的教父 知道吗？他刚出狱不久
This is Megan's godfather, okay? He just got out the joint.
你干嘛把我的事抖出来？
Why you putting all my business in the street?
- 他们叫他 - 我刚出狱 我可不想再回去了
- They call him… - I got out of jail. I ain't going back!
我不会再回去了
I ain't going back!
你怎么了？害怕了？以前没见过枪吗？
What's wrong with you? You're scared. You ain't seen a gun before?
别拿枪指着那小子 伙计
Stop pointing the gun at the boy.
听着 少在别人面前不尊重我
Look, don't you disrespect me in front of company.
把枪收起来
Let the gun go off.
小子 你是个又高又笨又大 长相滑稽的混蛋 是不是啊？
Nigga, you a big, tall, Ludacris- looking motherfucker, ain't you?
- 会饶舌吗？- 不会
- You rap? - No.
嗨 迈克
Hey, Mike!
现在听好了 10点01分送我女儿回到家
Now, listen. Have my daughter home at 10:01.
如果10点01分她还没到家 我会上车去找 懂吗？
If she ain't home at 10:01, I'm in the car, okay?
带上枪 找到你 然后把你的屁股打烂
Lock, loaded and hunting your motherfucking ass down.
- 听见我的话没？- 说啊 我会跟他一块追
- Do you hear me? Speak up. - I'll go with him.
要是我出马的话 晓得情形会怎样吗？嚓嚓砰砰 小子
If I'm there, know what it'll be? Chitty Chitty Bang Bang, nigga.
- 就会像那样 - 马库斯
- That's what it'll be. - Marcus!
雷吉 宝贝 真对不起 原谅梅根的爸爸和他的笨搭档
Reggie, baby, I am so sorry. Forgive Megan's dad and his silly friend.
- 你是处男？- 是的
- You a virgin? - Yes.
继续保持下去 今晚不准乱来
Keep it that way. Ain't gonna be no fucking tonight.
宝贝 这件红衬衫真不错 祝你们玩得开心
Baby, the red shirt's nice. You guys have a good time.
- 你跟男人上过床吗？- 没有
- You ever made love to a man? - No.
- 你想吗？- 不想 先生
- You want to? - No, sir.
- 嗨 玩开心点 宝贝儿 - 走吧 走吧
- Hey, have a good time, baby. - Go. Go.
- 好了 - 我们得走了
- All right. - We need to go.
你真是酷毙了
That was cool.
你准备好破这个案子吗？
So you ready to bust this case open?
哦 是的 让我们打个漂亮仗
Oh, yeah. Let's finish strong. All right?
好了 小姐们 今晚是我们最后的机会了 为了抓住塔皮亚
All right, ladies. We cannot take a burn tonight or Tapia walks.
我得干得干净利落
I need a good, clean break- in.
- 扎克 侦查哨就位了？- 已经就位
- Zank, eyeball. - Eyeball set.
- 德克斯 到高地了？- 已经上屋顶了
- Dex, high ground. - Rooftop set.
- 凡诺蒂 点着你的大麻烟 - 明白
- Fanuti, light your crack pipe. - Got you.
罗克曼 仪器都好了？
Lockman, you buzzing?
一切就绪 宝贝
We're up, baby.
- 喂？有人在吗？- 我们是来送尸的
- Hello, anybody home?! - We got a stiff to deliver!
- 怎么了 伙计？- 我们是来送尸的
- What's going on here, man? - We got a stiff to deliver.
- 这里没有人要过尸体 - 那家伙现在在车上 他刚死不久的
- Nobody told me about any stiff. - The guy's in the van now. He's fresh.
今晚我们不接受尸体
No deliveries tonight.
他们叫我们直接来这里的 就是这儿
They told us to come right over to the place. This is the place.
- 我们必须把他送进去 对不起 - 任何人都不准进来
- We must bring him in here. I'm sorry. - No one in.
- 你们把尸体送到停尸房了吗？- 停尸房？
- You get that body to the morgue yet? - Morgue?
你不是说要送到西班牙棕榈殡仪馆的吗？
You said to get it to the Spanish Palms Mortuary.
谁说的？你这个拉丁傻瓜
No, you dumb Latin fuck.
你大麻抽多了吧？
What you smoking in that crack pipe?
你他妈说谁是拉丁傻瓜？
Who you calling a Latin fuck, man?
该死
Check.
这下面是烧死人的 迈克
There's burnt people down here, Mike.
该死
Oh, fuck.
该死 谁的牙齿
Damn, somebody's teeth.
既然我们都过来了 你就签收一下吧
Now that we're here, you need to sign some paperwork…
因为这个家伙有传染病 可能会传染到你的
because the man is very contagious. His contagiousness could touch you.
祝你们晚安
You guys have a nice evening. Good night.
能让我们进去喝杯热可可吗？
Might you see us inside for some hot cocoa?
一号摄影机 信号良好 二号摄影机 信号良好
Cam one, I got a good signal. Cam two, I got a good signal.
- 该死 - 住手 今晚不许那么干
- Damn! - Stop it. Do not do that tonight.
- 你没闻到吗？- 哦 对 我闻到了
- You don't smell that? - Oh, yeah, I smell it.
- 臭死了 - 闭嘴
- It stinks. - Stop!
我要来点兴奋药
I'm gonna have some Pepto.
- 这位兄弟还没进行防腐处理 - 你说什么呢？
- This dude hasn't been embalmed yet. - What you talking about?
他们用一个管子插到你的喉咙里 吸干你身上所有的液体
They stick a tube down your throat and just suck out all the gunk and bile.
因为不那样的话 你的尸体就会充气 然后开始腐烂
Because what happens is, your body'll get gaseous and you'll decompose.
你不想那样去见你的家人吧
Don't want that to happen before your family see you.
- 我现在不需要知道这些 - 他们会把你的嘴巴缝上
- I don't need to know that now. - They sew your mouth closed.
必须要把所有的洞都堵上 因为死人常常会放屁
They got to get it all out because a lot of times dead people'll fart.
那样会把所有参加葬礼的人都熏跑的
That shit'll clear a funeral home out.
- 你从哪儿知道的这些东西？- 探索频道 我很喜欢看那个的
- How do you know all that? - Learning Channel. That shit got me.
哦 天啊
Oh, shit.
你都不需要先热热身吗？
You're not even gonna warm up to it?
嗨 干点警察该干的吧
Hey! Do some cop work.
- 他是个人啊 - 检查一下棺材
- He's a human being. - Check the casket.
你手在里面为什么不顺便检查一下他的脊柱呢？
Why don't you check his spine while you're in there.
我要吐了
I'm retching.
迈克
Mike!
- 干嘛？- 你正经点好不好
- What? - Have some dignity.
- 我什么都没做啊 - 把她的奶子遮起来
- I ain't doing nothing. - Cover her titties up.
我难道会对这对大奶子做什么吗？
Like, what am I gonna do with these big- ass dead titties?
但是你还在盯着它们看啊
But you're looking, though.
你 你脑子有问题
There's… Something's wrong with your brain.
把奶子盖上吧
Just cover the titties.
天杀的
Goddamn!
该死 这东西至少比有些摇篮要好
Damn. This nicer than some cribs.
她要被送去古巴
She's going to Cuba.
现在谁是顶级警察？呃？
Who's top cop now? Huh?
我说的吧 看到了？
That's what I'm talking about. See? There you go.
就是这些东西 照下这些钱 然后检查一下这具尸体
That's it right there. Take a picture of the money, then check this body.
不 我要数一数这钱 知道吗？
Nah, I'm gonna count these. You know?
检查尸体去
Check the body.
我会去的 迈克 只是我不是很着急罢了
I'm gonna check the body, Mike. I'm not rushing into it, that's all.
这具要被送到洛杉矶的一个停尸房去
This one's going to a mortuary in L.A.
我来检查这具
I'm gonna check this one.
我说你不行吧
That's that bullshit that I be talking about.
迈克 他那该死的头盖骨掉下来了
Mike, the motherfucking head fell off.
过来
Come here.
我回来了
I'm back in the game.
我想我找到什么了
Think I got something.
感觉像是个袋子
Feels like a bag.
该死 是他的肾
Shit, it's his kidney.
我闻到死人的味道了
I smell dead people.
毒品和钱 我们抓到他的把柄了 宝贝儿
Drugs and money. We got him, baby.
这家伙的里面全塞满了
This dude is loaded.
他肯定以为他是个天才 居然可以想到用死尸来运送毒品
Bet he thinks he's a damn genius, transporting them in dead bodies.
我们去取尸体
Let's get this body.
迈克 来人了
Mike, you got company, man.
有人过来了 躲起来 把毒品给我 把它给我
Somebody's coming. Hide! Give me the X. Give me the X.
你们得去拖延一下
You gotta stall them.
躲起来 躲起来
Hide! Hide! Hide!
该死
Shit!
小流氓干的？去看一下
Punk kids do this? Go check it out.
躲起来
Hide!
马库斯 你干嘛要？那可不是个好主意 伙计
Marcus! Why would you… That's just not smart, man.
你要是告诉特丽莎 我会杀了你的
You tell Theresa, I'll kill you.
下一个是那小妞
Bimbo's next.
哦 上帝 不要那具 不要动那小妞
Oh, God. Not that. Not the bimbo.
我们动作要快一点
Let's hurry this shit up.
该死
Shit.
我们有大麻烦了 我们有大麻烦了
We got a big problem. We got a big problem.
快把救护车开进屋来
Drive that ambulance into the building right now.
- 撞进来 - 不 我不行 伙计
- Crash it into the building! - No. Not me, baby.
我的撞车记录太多了 你来吧
I got too many crashes on my file. You do it.
你别开玩笑了 上个月我才因为撞车被警告过
No. You're kidding. I got red- flagged last month for the thing.
你知道政府赔了多少吗？我可不想再来一次了
You know how much the city paid. I can't have another ding on my file.
迈克 我说兄弟 我们是想帮你的 但是
Mike, my man, we want to help you out here, you know…
但是我们这儿有点行政上的问题 知道吗？
but we got a couple of administration problems over here, you know?
要不我们把警笛和警灯开开？
So how about we give sirens and some flashing lights?
闹腾两下 怎么样？
Make a racket. How's that?
不行 不行
Negative! Negative!
把救护车撞进来 马上
Crash that ambulance into the building right now!
我们真的愿意效劳 但是
We want to help the team out and everything, but…
我们不能再因撞车而被停职了
But I'm not getting suspended for this.
好啊 一会儿我出去马上就踢你们俩的屁股
Okay, I plan on whupping y'all asses the second I get out of here.
- 把车撞进来 马上 - 好吧
- Crash into the building right now! - Screw it.
为了警察的工作不惜一切
Just the price of cop business.
把她抬到手术台上
Now, get her on the table.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God.
靠 怎么回事？我实在 我实在
Jeez! What the hell! I'm so… I'm so…
这可真惨 伙计们
That's tragic, man.
快快快 后门没人 快快
Go, go, go. Back door's clear. Go! Go!
快起来 马库斯
Get up, Marcus!
我的油门被卡住了 我不是故意的
The gas got stuck. I didn't mean to.
啊 天哪
Oh, man.
柔软的真皮
Supple leather, you know.
你从没摸过你车里的皮吧？
You ever rub your leather?
就这么触摸 感觉可好了
You know, like, just rub it. See how good it feeIs.
你对爱情到底是怎么看的 迈克？
What does love mean to you, Mike?
我和我的爱情不需要你来操心
Don't worry about me and my love.
我生命中有足够的爱了
Look, I got plenty of love in my life.
就像女人的屁股一样
Like a woman's butt.
- 别闹了 - 啊 啊 啊 迈克
- Don't do that. - Whoa, whoa, whoa. Mike.
集中注意力 我们要争取到搜查令
Let's just concentrate and get this warrant.
但我需要表达一下
I need to express right now.
我要你知道 这是我们最后一次合作 我很感谢你
I want you to know, if this is our last job, I really appreciate you.
懂吗？
Okay?
这不是「同性恋」的话
No, this is not gay shit.
这是男人之间的话 知道我什么意思吗？
This is man shit. You know what I mean?
而且你真是个帅哥 知道吗？
And you a beautiful man. You know?
而且你有真善美的一面
And when you let the beautiful side…
- 干嘛？- 看看你自己的瞳孔
- What? - Look at your pupils.
我怎么看自己的瞳孔啊？怎么看？
How am I look at my pupil? What, I'm…
你刚才吃什么了？你是不是在那儿吃了迷幻药？
Yo, what are you taking? Did you take some of that X?
- 嗨 来 我们拥抱一下 - 嗨 听着听着 你给我听着
- Hey, look, give me a hug. - Hey, get off. Listen, listen. Listen!
我们需要这个搜查令 别弄砸了 正经点
We need this warrant. Do not fuck this up. Pull yourself together.
晚上好 警长
Evening, captain.
您好
Hello…
警长
"capteeon."
好啊 你们今晚打算怎么整我啊？
So how do you two plan to fuck up my evening tonight?
警长 相信我 如果没有非常非常重要的事情
Well, captain, believe me, we would not be here…
我们是不会来找您的
if it weren't seriously, utterly important.
进来吧
Get in here.
把手拿开
Get off me!
头儿 这儿真漂亮
Cap, this is beautiful.
您家可真温馨
Have such a warm feel, you know.
就像那个叫什么「疯衰」 叫什么来着的 迈克？
Sort of like a "ving shwa." What's it, Mike?
- 是V打头的词 像「疯傻」 - 你不能坐下吗？
- It was a V, like a "von schwo." - Why don't you have a seat?
- 或者叫「风沙」 或者 - 是「风水」
- Or "ven wangs" or… - Feng shui.
「风水」
"Von sway."
您的家真是个风水宝地啊
You have a "von sway" home.
谢谢 请随意
Make yourseIf at home.
警长 我知道你说过我们不能动强尼·塔皮亚
All right, captain, I know you said that Johnny Tapia was hands…
不行 绝对不行
Oh, no! No!
看 警长 现在我们找到证据了 这个是掩护
Look, captain, we got him. It's a wrap.
看 我们今天折腾了一天 但我们搞到证据了
Look, we messed up today, but we got him.
就请您看下吧
Please just look.
- 我怎么换下一张？- 按这就可以了
- How do I move it? - Here, you flip through the pictures.
按这里 就可以看下一张
You can flip… You can flip through picture…
哦 太恐怖了
This is horrible.
- 迈克 给我照个像 - 你可以放大一些看
- Take the picture. - You can look really close.
看 我们已经掌握了所有证据 可以马上制他于死地
Listen, we got everything that we need to take this dude.
哦 真恶心
Oh, God.
他们把内脏都取出来了
They're taking the organs out.
就在这 你可以 对 就看这里
Right there you can… You can… Yeah. If you look there…
哦 天啊
Oh, gosh.
很好 这太触目惊心了
This is good. That's horrible.
看看这个
Look at this.
大家只是需要放松
Everybody just needs to relax. Whoosah. Whoosah. Whoosah.
你干吗呢 马库斯？现在是凌晨2点 把手拿开
What are you doing? Marcus, it's 2 a.m. Get your hands off me.
还记得我们说过要给维加斯和雷伊斯打电话吗？
Remember we said we were gonna call Vargas and Reyes?
- 不 我不记得了 - 给维加斯打电话
- No, I don't… - Call Vargas!
跟他说我们打算说的话
Tell him the thing we said to tell him.
- 什么话？- 跟他说 关于昨天
- What thing? - Tell him we said… About yesterday.
就是那件事
And tell him about the thing.
警长 我们还有录影做证据
So, captain, listen, we've also got videotape.
昨天我们确实搞砸了 但现在他跑不了
Yesterday, we fucked up bad. But we got him now.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
- 怎么啦？- 没事 好多时候都是这样
- What? - No, a lot of times with these…
哦 该死
Oh, shit!
- 怎 怎么啦？我把照片删除了？- 没事 我们还有录影
- What? Did I erase it? - No. We got video.
- 我们把那该死的放在 - 啊 让我看看
- We got fucking… - Oh. Let me see.
哦 天啊
Oh, shit.
他通过尸体来把毒品运送到全国各地
He's shipping the drugs around the country in bodies.
我们还发现了装钞票的棺材 是运往古巴的
We found coffins of cash, tagged for Cuba.
你认为塔皮亚准备卷钱逃跑？
And you think Tapia's about to move out with all this money?
啊 我最爱听你叫我兔子鼻
I love it when you call me Bunny Nose.
该死
Shit!
当然 宝贝儿
Yeah, I do, girl.
你真该看看我弄来的这些性感的东西
You should see this sexy shit I got on.
你跟谁打电话呢？
Who the hell are you talking to?
我在跟维加斯 和
I talked to Vargas and…
雷伊斯 他们说他们马上就来
Ru- Reyes. They said that they're down for whatever.
这是条好鱼
This is a nice fish, you know.
靠 大贼眼 但还是条好鱼
Big fucking eyes, but a nice fucking fish.
警长 我们需要搜查令
We need this warrant, captain.
让我们把这个混蛋拉下马吧
Let's take this scumbag down.
这该死的到底是怎么回事？
What the fuck is going on?
- 他吞了两颗迷幻药 - 你没事吧 老兄 放松
- He ingested X. - You okay, pal? Take it easy.
好 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
医师说一定让他保持冷静
Poison lady says we gotta keep him cool.
不然的话 他会烧起来 会损害大脑
Otherwise, he's burning up, he can get brain damage.
那样也没人会觉察到
Nobody'll even notice that.
迈克 我下面硬起来了
Mike, I got an erection.
赶快送我回家
Take me home.
给我老婆打电话 说我马上到家
Call the wife, tell her I'm on the way.
你们听得见我吗？
Hope you guys hear me.
- 听到她了 非常清楚 - 她进去了
- We got her. Loud and clear. - She's in.
好戏开始了
Showtime.
A组 突袭棕榈停尸房
Palm Mortuary, Alpha team.
D组去塔皮亚的大宅子 B组负责迪克西号的码头
Tapia's mansion, DeIta. Dixie Boy boat dock, Bravo.
海岸警卫队会负责所有的水域截击
Coast Guard gunships, anything that hits the water.
我们同时突袭三个地点
We hit all three places simultaneously.
8：45出发 9点整行动
Tac up at 08:45. We go hot at 09:00 sharp.
把警笛大开
Bring the noise.
你真是个漂亮姑娘
You're such a beautiful girl.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 强尼 - 干嘛？
- Johnny. - Yeah?
- 她是黑鬼吗？- 别说了 妈妈
- Is she a Negro? - Please, Mama!
闭嘴 滚出去
Shut up! Get out of here!
你自己的事 自己处理吧
You make your bed, you sleep in it!
让开让开
Make way!
- 趴下 - 不许动
- Get down! - Don't fucking move!
你敢于冒险 我喜欢
You take risks. I like that.
或者
Or…
也许我在为你而冒险？
maybe I'm the one taking a risk on you. Huh?
- 是吗？- 当然
- Yeah? - Yeah.
对不起 老板 我必须和你说点事
Excuse me, boss. We need to talk now.
外边出什么事了？
Something's going on outside.
- 警察 - 你什么意思 警察？
- Cops. - What the fuck do you mean, cops?
该死的
Goddamn it.
我们是美国毒品稽查局的 你们不要进去
DEA. You don't plan on entering, do you?
- 我们有搜查令 - 我们有卧底在里面 必须让她先出来
- We have a warrant to get in there. - A UC's inside. She's gotta leave first.
给你们两分钟
You got two minutes.
- 打她手机 - 是
- Call her on her cell. - Yes, sir.
把房子的电源切断
Cut the power to the house.
- 找到她了吗？- 快点啊 还没有
- You got her? Well, let's go. - No, sir.
我们这里有情况
We got a bogey.
这是为了你 约瑟夫 还有我和母亲俄国
God. This is for you, Josef, and me and Mother Russia.
他们不是什么强盗 而是真的警察
They're not gangbanger homeys. They're cops.
警察？
Cops?!
他们不是来抢我们的货的 我看他们在保护她
They weren't trying to hit the load. I think they were looking after her.
现在 你老实告诉我
Now, you tell me…
- 窃听器在哪儿？- 他们识破她了
- where is the wire? - They made her.
我们需要把她救出来 快
We gotta get her out. Go! Come on!
嗨 塔皮亚 你该死的混蛋
Hey, Tapia, you fucking mother.
俄国的家伙来了
The Russian Grim Reaper is here.
所有东西都应该在这
Everything's in here.
- 哦 该死 - 该死的
- Oh, shit. - Goddamn.
监视的 前两个小时有人进出停尸房吗？
Eyeball, has anything left this mortuary in the past two hours?
一个葬礼车队刚离开 我们一直跟踪到迈阿密港
A four-hearse funeral just left. We trailed them to Miami Harbor.
迈阿密空警 塔皮亚想把钱运去古巴 调直升机来
Miami Air, Tapia's running his money to Cuba. Get us a chopper!
嗨 塔皮亚
Hey, Tapia!
你怕我吗？你这个狗杂种
You scared of me, you little scumbag?!
- 我们有麻烦了 - 把车转到后面去
- We got some heat. - Pull the car back.
我该死的要杀了你 你该死的算老几？
I'll fucking kill you! Who the hell are you?
- 放下武器 - 放下武器 马上
- Drop the weapon! - Drop the weapon now!
- 我和你们一边的 - 放下武器
- I'm with you guys! - Put it down, now!
- 我在这 - 闭嘴
- I'm over here! - Shut up!
- 放下武器 - 我要杀了那狗娘养的
- Drop the weapon! - I'll kill that son of a bitch!
这是A组 我们将和B组还有海岸警卫队会合
This is Alpha. Heads up to the Coast Guard Sharks and Bravo Team.
关闭港口 拦住任何行动中的船只
Close the harbor. Freeze any moving speedboat.
这里是B组
This is Bravo.
我们发现一条形迹可疑的快艇 正在离开港口
We got a go- fast slinging a high rate of speed down Miami harbor.
拦住这船
Stop that boat.
他们想甩掉我们
This guy's moving us.
他们朝大桥下开去了
Think we're going for the bridge.
海岸警队 我们上了
Coast Guard, we're going in.
迈阿密警察 立即停船
Miami Police. Shut it down.
这里是警察 立即停船
This is the police. Shut it down.
- 注意 他们有武器 - 退后
- Watch out, he got a weapon. - Bail out!
海岸警卫队 准备射击 烧了他们
Coast Guard, take him down. Burn him.
船已被截停 船已被截停
Vessel is dead in the water. Vessel is dead in the water.
这就是我们要干的
This is what we do.
哦 都在这里
Oh, man, it's full up. It's full up.
这次是正义的行动
It's a righteous bust.
他们怎么跑掉的？
How the hell they slip away?
给我接监视警长
Give me the watch commander on the horn.
你知道她哥哥在迈阿密警察局吗？把他找来
Do you know her brother on Miami PD? Find him.
你知道谁会来救你吗？
Do you know anyone who might want to save your life?
- 喂？- 马库斯 他们
- Hello? - Marcus, they…
你拿了我一亿美元
You have $ 100 million of mine…
我要你48小时内给我还回来
and I want it back in 48 hours.
麻烦大了
Shit just got real.
杰克斯·奈尔 美国毒品缉查局
Jack Snell, DEA.
艾梅斯特工 联邦调查局的
Agent Eames, FBl…
他们刚告诉我
who has just informed me…
卫星监测到 二十分钟前 塔皮亚的飞机进入了古巴领空
that satellite pinpointed Tapia's jet in Cuban airspace 20 minutes ago.
古巴？
Cuba?
美国的政策是不和绑架者谈判
United States does not negotiate with hostage- takers.
特别是古巴的绑架者
Especially Cuban hostage- takers.
现在的情况很棘手
It's a delicate situation.
这不是什么情况 她是我妹妹
This is not just a situation. This is my sister.
国家的所有机构都在通过非正式途径
Off the record, all State Department agencies…
以外交方式解决问题
are using their back-channel contacts for a diplomatic solution.
你们知道 当外交途径办完事后
You know, by the time y'all finish being diplomatic…
我妹妹可能已经死了 这都他妈是废话
my sister could be in a fucking box. This is bullshit.
我们不会轻易放过他的
He ain't getting away from us that easy.
我们一同狂飙
We ride together…
生死与共
we die together.
永远都是坏小子
Bad boys for life.
我们自己动手 伙计
We just gotta do it ourselves, man.
我不认识你们
I don't know you.
但看起来你们要干蠢事了 我也加入
You look like you're about to do something stupid. I'm in.
你们还不知道 我们这些前三角洲部队队员有多厉害吧？
Dodd tell you how crazy us ex-Delta guys are?
我兄弟 蒂多 住在古巴
My brother, Tito, lives in Cuba.
他有点疯狂 但他和反抗军有联系
He's a little crazy, but he's hooked up with the underground.
武器 人员 还有躲避的地点 我们正需要
Weapons, men, a safe house. Whatever we need.
别再考虑什么护照之类的东西
You can forget about passports and all that stuff.
因为一旦古巴方面抓到咱们 咱们都会死
Because if the Cubans catch us, we're all dead.
我兄弟是地下反抗卡斯楚的组织A66的成员
My brother Tito's in Alpha 66, the Anti- Castro Underground.
这跟塔皮亚有什么关系？
What does that have to do with Tapia?
当然有 塔皮亚是卡斯楚最大的毒品资金的来源
Everything. Tapia's the biggest supplier of drug cash to Castro.
所以地下组织也反对他
So Alpha 66 will be all over him.
兄弟 现在时机再好不过了 他说马上就能安排
Brother, that is perfect. He says he can get men on the tunnel right away.
我跟他联系
Let me holler at him.
蒂多 我们需要地图 隐蔽地点 还有其他所有东西
Tito, we need layout, security, the whole deal.
我们得到情报塔皮亚明天下午4点有批货要进
We got info that Tapia's got a casket coming in tomorrow at 4:00 p.m.
很好 这是进去的好机会 好
Yeah, that might be our way in. Yeah.
给你们带来了个帮忙的 是CIA的
Brought you a little care package from my friends over at the CIA.
他们要来帮助 别问我为什么
They want to help. And don't ask me.
他们是间谍
They're spies.
前三角洲情报和爆破专家 申请加入行动
Former Delta Intel and Demo. Requesting permission to tag along.
罗尼 听说古巴湾外有一条船抛锚了
Ronnie, I hear there's a boat on fire off the coast of Cuba.
我们可以在国际水域帮助他们
Shouldn't we break international waters to help them?
我就是这个意思
That's my dog.
得破釜沉舟了
Point of no return.
我从心底感谢你们
I want to thank y'all from the bottom of my heart.
- 迈克 听着 - 等我回去再跟我说吧
- Mike, look, I just… - Tell me when we get back.
目标进入 我看见那艘船了
The target's in sight. I see the boat.
明白 目标正前方 300码
Roger. Target 12 o'clock. 300 yards.
打开门 准备
Roper in the door. Stand by.
下 下 下
Go! Go! Go!
- 蒂多？- 欢迎来到古巴
- Tito? - Welcome to Cuba.
和塔皮亚对门也算是的隐蔽地点啊
Damn. What's up with the safe house across the street from Tapia's crib?
但这是最安全的地方了
This is the last place anyone would look.
我们一直在监视他的大宅子
We've been watching the place.
卫兵们每天下午3点半准时踢足球
Guards play soccer each day at 3:30.
坏消息是 所有人都知道他用正规军当他的个人保镖
The bad news, everyone knows he uses the army like his bodyguards.
- 这就是塔皮亚的住宅区 - 是CIA的东西吧？
- This is Tapia's compound. - CIA hooked us up, huh?
这是最尖端的激光雷达技术 甚至能看到他的逃跑地道
Yeah. This LIDAR laser technology even shows his escape tunnel.
报警系统一直连到军队营地
The alarm security is wired to the army.
如果我们行动前不把这个安全设施炸掉 就麻烦了
We're screwed if we don't blow up this security room before we make a move.
我们自己挖的地道四通八达
The tunnel we're digging branches off.
一条通到他家后院 另外一条通到他的逃脱通道
One under his back yard and the other into his escape tunnel.
我们动作要快
We gotta hurry up.
看 我跟你说我弟弟是个疯子吧？
See? I told you my brother was a maniac.
- 你觉得怎么样？- 让我看看
- How we looking? - Let me check it out.
老爸 你长得像耶稣
Papi, you look like Jesus.
他们为什么叫这 最后的晚餐？
Why they call this The Last Supper?
这是他们在耶稣受难前 最后一次共进晚餐
It was the last time they were all together before Jesus was crucified.
上十字架？
Crucified?
把耳朵堵住 嗨 听着
Hold your ears. Hey, you.
这也太该死的消沉了 明白不明白？
Listen to me. This is fucking depressing! You understand?!
这该死的是谁的想法？
I mean, who had this fucking idea?
我只要美丽的小天使看着我
I just want little angels looking down on me.
这里是海滩 离塔皮亚的家只有300码
Okay, here's the ocean, 300 yards from Tapia's house.
我们在这儿 隐蔽地点 第一条通道在这里
We're here. Safe house. First tunnel comes through to here.
第一组拿掉安全设施
First team takes out the security station.
第二通道直达房子的中心
Second tunnel comes through into the center of the house.
蒂多 你的内线说西德妮在最后一个卧室
Tito, your contacts inside said Syd's in the last bedroom…
第二层 对吗？
on the second floor, right?
露比是我们的人 如果她说你妹妹在那儿
Lupe's one of us. If she says your sister's there…
那她就一定在那儿
she is there.
三点整 一大袋的猫和蜥蜴会被仍过铁丝网
Three o'clock sharp, the bag of cats and iguanas go over the fence.
希望这会让安全人员烦躁并关掉报警系统
Hopefully the motion detectors'll go so crazy security'll shut them off.
我们的人将在外面掩护 防止军队进入
My guys will watch the outside for any military.
他们一来 就麻烦大了
If they come, that's bad.
咱们努力成功吧 伙计们
Let's make this count, guys.
我们进去了
We're in.
该死 这已经是今天的第五次了
Goddamn it, it's the fifth time today.
卡洛斯 把行动探测仪关了 等修好再说
Carlos, turn off the motion sensors till we get it fixed.
- 看 爸爸 我找到了一只猫 我可以养它吗？- 不行
- Look what I found. Can I keep them? - No.
好了 兄弟们
All right, guys…
- 探测器停止工作了 时间到了 - 开始行动
- sensors are down. Time to move. - We are 100% go.
行动
Let's go.
左 左 啊 比看起来难多了
Left. Left. Yeah. There we go. This is not as easy as it looks.
好 我们到路口了 分头行动
Okay, we're at the T. Split right.
祝好运 兄弟们
Good luck, guys.
快 快
Let's go. Come on, let's go.
我们来找足球场 用用你的鼻子 宝贝儿 把它找出来
Find the soccer game. Sniff it out, baby. Sniff it out.
往左 往左 该死
To the left. To the left. Oh, shit.
哦 你们别看到我 别看到
Oh, you did not see me.
- 我们准备好攻入逃脱通道了 - 好 这里是足球场了
- Ready to bust into the escape tunnel. - There we go. Soccer.
抱歉
Sorry.
走走走 快
Go, go, go, go, go!
行动
Go!
把那个美国婊子抓下来
Get me the American bitch.
给桑托司将军打电话 我需要他 马上
Call General Santos. Tell him I need him now!
对不起 宝贝儿 把她带到安全地带 快
Sorry, darling. Take her outside to safety. Come on.
- 卡洛斯 情况不妙 - 我知道
- Carlos, this is not good! - I know!
- 桑托司将军呢？- 老板 他快到了
- Where is GeneraI Santos?! - He's coming, boss!
你们这帮美国佬 我要把你们脑袋打掉
You fucking maricons! I'm gonna blow your head off!
该死
Fuck!
这枪怎么了？我儿子会把你们煮了吃
What's happened to this gun? My son will slice you into chorizo.
- 老妈 抱歉了 - 你这个混小子
- Mama, I'm very sorry. - You little puta!
- 维加斯 进来了吗？- 我们把母亲和小女孩都抓到了
- Vargas, you in? - We got Mama and the girl.
我们要进屋了 冲
We're entering the house. Go!
快 快 快
Move! Move! Move!
所有人都清理了 我们最多还有30秒 快
Everything's clear outside. You got 30 seconds max. Haul ass.
阳台上有两个 我打不到
You got two rovers on the balcony. I can't get a shot off.
看见了吗？我没打中
See the rover? I missed him!
爬下 爬下
Get down! Get down now!
- 趴下 - 趴下
- Get down! - Down!
快 快 快
Move! Move! Move!
- 马库斯 - 来呀
- Marcus! - Come on!
快 我们救到人质了
Move! We got the package.
你们要加快 情况越来越紧张了
Move now. It's turning into a real bad day.
- 维加斯 我们要出来了 掩护我们 - 我们掩护你 伙计
- Vargas, we're coming back. Cover us! - We got you covered, baby.
有谁告诉我情况怎么样了？
Somebody talk to me. What's going on?
军队已经到了
The military is everywhere.
- 糟了 我们要走了 - 听着 我们这来了很多敌人
- This is bad, I have to go. - Listen, you have a lot of company.
赶快出来
Get out of there now!
我中弹了
I'm hit! I'm hit!
去地道 我把它炸了
Head for the tunnel. I'll blow this.
快 出去
Go, go! Get out!
迈克 你们必须出来
Mike, you gotta get out.
维加斯 撤 马上
Vargas! Get out! Abort!
我们没有时间去地道了 改用B计划
We won't reach the tunnel! Go to plan B.
- 我们现在实行B计划 - 什么B计划？
- We're going to plan B! - What plan B?!
你从来不注意听讲
You don't pay attention to shit!
- B计划是什么？- 那是你的问题
- What's the plan B? - That's your problem!
你开什么玩笑？你们能不能闭嘴 走吧
Are you fucking shitting me? Let's go!
- 跟着我 跟着我 - 我会的
- Follow me! Follow me! - I will…
B计划 什么是B计划？
Plan B? What the hell is plan B?
- 蒂多 你在这里干什么？- 你需要一个古巴向导 傻瓜
- Tito, what you doing here? - You need a Cuban guide, fool.
这边
This way!
- 他们没法到地道 - 咱们撤出去吧
- They won't make it to the tunnel. - Let's blow out of here!
钥匙 钥匙
Keys, keys, keys!
哦 我的天哪 不 天啊
Oh, my God! No! God! Oh, my God!
B计划里可没考虑到敌人会有机枪的
Plan B did not have that big- ass gun in it!
你管这个叫B计划？B计划是指的什么？狗屎
You call this plan B?! What the plan B stand for? Bullshit!
你想要自己开车吗？
Do you want to drive?!
好啊 就停在那些开着机枪的混蛋们旁边吧
Yeah, pull over by the fuckers with the machine guns!
该死
Shit!
想杀我
I am not to be fucked with!
你开车通过餐厅的时候 我错过了那帮人的会议
I missed the part of the meeting when you drive through the dining room.
然后正好冲出前门
And right out the front door.
快上卡车
Get in the truck!
到处都是古巴军队
Cuban army was everywhere.
- 带我们去关塔那摩湾 - 不不不不
- Gotta get us to Guantanamo Bay! - No.
你不能冒然开车进入美国海军基地
You can't drive onto a U.S. Naval base.
我们可是美国人
Hey, we're Americans, okay?
马库斯 你知道平常我们碰到这种情况时
Marcus, you know how when we usually get in these situations…
我总是会想方设法让你感觉好一点
I'm always trying to make you feel better,
好像我们会逢凶化吉一样
like we'll be all right.
- 是啊 是啊 - 我本也可以说的
- Yeah, yeah. - I could say it…
但大家都知道那只是胡说八道
but that'd be a bunch of bulIshit today.
军队 军队
Military, military.
- 走哪边？哪边？- 不 右边 右边 向右转
- Which way?! - No, right! Right! Go right!
这里是毒贩子们的老窝 是他们制造毒品的地方
These are drug dealer shacks. They make cocaine here.
希望那里有会爆炸的东西
Hope there's shit in there that likes to blow.
快点 我要杀了你们这些狗娘养的
Faster! I'll kill you, motherfucker!
我要冲过去了
I'm gonna go for it.
- 这山该死的真高 - 该死
- This is a big-ass hill. - Shit.
- 这也是B计划的一部分吗？- 不 这是C计划
- Oh, shit! Is this still called plan B? - No, this is definitely plan C.
哦 耶稣啊
Oh, Jesus!
上帝啊
God! God!
所有人 开始还击啊
Everybody start shooting at somebody!
开枪 开枪
Shoot! Shoot!
- 该死 我没子弹了 - 我还有两颗子弹
- Shit! I'm out! - I got two rounds left.
- 枪膛里还有一颗子弹 - 我没子弹了
- One in the chamber. - I'm out.
这么多枪 难道一颗子弹都没有吗？
All these guns and none of you got no bullets?!
- 我屁股里还有一颗 - 哦 天啊 他中弹了
- I got one in my hip! - Oh, God, he's hit!
那边 关塔那摩
There! Gitmo!
美国领土 宝贝儿 美国领土
U.S. soil, baby. U.S. soil.
快 快走
Come on! Go!
- 美国人来了 - 哦 小心
- Americans on the way! - Whoa, watch…
冲过去 冲过去
Run it! Run it!
快
Go.
快 快 快
Go! Go! Go!
该死
Fuck.
迈克
Mike!
我们是美国人
We're Americans!
我给你们纳过税了 射他们
I pay my motherfucking taxes! Shoot them!
该死的外国佬 放下枪
Hey, fucking gringo. Drop the gun!
放下枪 放下枪
Put it down! Put it down!
他们帮不了你了 你会留在古巴
They can't help you. You're staying in Cuba.
你们现在站在雷区
You are standing on a live minefield!
不要动
Do not move!
听着 为什么我们不都回家去呢？
Look, why don't we all go home…
嗯 我们回家 你去旅馆
Well, we'll go home, you go to a hotel.
这笔帐以后再算 今天我们都占不了便宜
Work this shit out another day. None of us is having a good day right now.
- 把枪给我 - 好的
- Give me the gun! - Okay.
我要把枪扔到你的脚下
I'll toss it right at your feet…
就扔在那颗地雷的旁边
right next to the mine.
你就该那样开枪
Now, that's how you supposed to shoot!
从现在开始 你就该那么开枪
From now on, that's how you shoot!
哦 我希望我的下一任搭档也能那样开枪
Oh, I want my next partner to shoot just like that.
只有功能紊乱的混蛋才能正好射中人家的脑门
It take a dysfunctionaI motherfucker to bust somebody in the head like that.
那是功能紊乱的表现之一
That's some dysfunctionaI shit.
不过我还希望下一个搭挡 会请我去参加他的家庭烤肉会
My next partner'll invite me to his barbecues, though.
过来 姑娘 过来
Come here, girl. Come here.
我大老远跑来古巴就是为了这个的
I came all the way to Cuba for this.
过来
Come on.
你们非得在这些地雷中间干这个吗？
Y'all gotta do that around land mines?
你们能告诉他们 在地雷中间干那个很危险吗？
Would you tell them that that shit is dangerous around these land mines?
你知道吗？迈克 承认这个对我来说很不容易
You know, Mike, this ain't easy for me,
但是我确实是错了
but I was wrong.
我会因为你跟我妹妹约会 感到骄傲的
I'll be very proud for you to date my sister.
- 谢谢 伙计 - 不客气
- Thanks, man. - All right.
知道吗 我和西德妮曾考虑过
You know, me and Syd thought about it…
那时候你的行为是那么疯狂
and your behavior was so crazy that…
我们每次都想尝试 可最后还是决定最好不告诉 你知道
any magic we could've captured, probably best if we didn't… You know.
你是准备占我妹妹的便宜吧？
You're just gonna take advantage of my little sister?
难道你已经伤了她的心？
Already you breaking her heart?
- 你说什么呢？- 她对你来说还不够好？
- What you talking about? - She not good enough for you?
西德妮 迈克说你狗屁不如
Syd, Mike says you ain't shit!
为什么你要这么大声地说些屁话呢？
Now, why would you scream out some crazy nonsense like that?
我不喜欢你到我家来 在我的新泳池里对我不敬
I don't appreciate you coming here, disrespecting me in my new pool.
你的新泳池是我出钱买的
I bought your new pool.
那你为什么不把这泳池挂在你的法拉利后面拖走呢？
Why don't you hook this pool up to your Ferrari and drag it out of here?
首先 我是在开玩笑
First of all, I was joking.
其次 就在此时此地 你该问问你自己
And second of all, all this right here, smell yourself right now.
因为此时此刻你又开始发疯了
Because this moment is what's wrong with you.
我的调职信还在废纸篓里呢
I got the transfer papers in the trash can.
我要把他们拼起来粘好
I'll get them and glue them the fuck up.
- 粘起来 - 什么？
- Glue them up. - What?
- 需要胶水吗？- 我们以后不会再是搭档了
- Want some glue? - We won't be partners no more.
我车里有胶水
I got glue in the car.
我正试图跟你好好谈谈
I'm trying to talk to you.
太热了 我觉得自己就好像要被煮熟了
It's hot, I feel like I'm cooking in this fucker…
可我还得在这儿听你说屁话？那首先
and I gotta hear shit out of you? Then on top of that shit…
你竟敢骗我的妹妹？
you gonna dog my baby sister?
哦 该死的又来了
Oh, this that bullshit!
爸爸
Dad!
我还留着保单 我还留着保单
I kept the warranty. I kept the warranty!
拜托 伙计 你得去背背歌词了
Come on, you gotta learn the words.
迈克 你不也不知道那该死的歌词吗？
Mike, you don't know the damn words either.